<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-10-15T21:06:34+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">new york novice</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/new-york-novice/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="new york novice"/><published>2025-10-12T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-10-12T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/new-york-novice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/new-york-novice/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Note:</strong> I apologize in advance about the slider functionality not working for the images 😔. Also, this visit happened in March 2025 but I was too busy and didn’t get the chance to write about my trip until now LOL</p> <hr/> <h3 id="purpose">purpose</h3> <p>During my last semester of college, I was interning full-time at Mercury (40 hr/wk) while also serving as one of Data 101’s head teaching assistants (20 hr/wk) alongside a reduced courseload. It was no doubt the busiest semester of my life, but I don’t have any regrets from taking on all that work.</p> <p>One of my closest friends, Irene, was wrapping up her last semester of her masters program at Cornell Tech and I’ve never been to New York before, so the logical choice was to obviously work from Mercury’s New York office while simultaneously spending spring break there.</p> <p>The trip was from 3/21/2025 to 3/29/2025, and this is what I ended up doing as a first time visitor to New York while working for some of the days (indicated with 💻). I actually planned on taking three days off from work but I ended up going into the office to get free breakfast and was too scared to leave after seeing everyone hard at work which resulted in me working as well LOL.</p> <p>Huge <strong>HUGE</strong> shoutout to Irene for letting me stay over at her place while also taking the time/effort to help with planning for this trip alongside from school to hangout with me :’)</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="friday-321">friday, 3/21</h4> <ul> <li>Work</li> <li>Go to airport</li> <li>Flight from SFO to JFK airport</li> </ul> <p>I had a red-eye flight so this was just a usual day of work and school, then I went to the airport.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="saturday-322">saturday, 3/22</h4> <ul> <li>Flight lands @ John F Kennedy airport</li> <li>Drop off stuff at Irene’s apartment</li> <li>Visit the Rockefeller area</li> <li>Brunch @ Black Seed Bagels</li> <li>Museum of Art and Design</li> <li>Snack at Central Park (Magnolia Bakery)</li> <li>Watch Moulin Rouge</li> <li>NBA Store + Bryant Park</li> <li>Dinner @ Sushi Hayashi</li> </ul> <p>My flight landed pretty early so we had a full day of playing (a term used by my friends and I to denote hanging out, kind of like 玩 in Mandarin) ahead of us. After living in the Bay Area for all of my life and hating how terrible the public transportation system is there, it was refreshing to use the NY subway system. While it’s not as complex as Japan’s and I admittedly got lost once or twice in NY, it’s still extremely efficient and easy to use to get around NY. I believe you can get different types of transit cards depending on your usage frequency, but each subway ride is $2.90 no matter the distance which has its pros and cons. Within a week, there is a maximum limit of 12 paid rides (exact information <a href="https://www.mta.info/fares-tolls/subway-bus/tap-and-ride">here</a>) so once that threshold is reached, each additional ride is free!</p> <p>Irene was so kind and considerate to wake up early to meet me halfway to help me get to her apartment since I’m just a tad directionally challenged. Cornell Tech is a pretty small campus compared to our alma mater, Berkeley, since it’s located on Roosevelt Island but its facilities are new, close to one another, and the area is super safe since it’s somewhat of a residential area. Roosevelt Island is also a tourist attraction so a lot of people take the tram to visit the island, which was also a nice experience.</p> <p>After dropping off my stuff, we visited the Rockefeller Area since I wanted to see Top of the Rock. We also got brunch at Black Seed Bagels since it’s within the area and we needed to save our stomachs for our dinner. A lot of people mentioned that going up Top of the Rock has really nice views (especially at night) but I skipped out on it since I’ve seen a lot of city views already. New York bagels are very famous and the ham bagel I got was pretty good, but it didn’t blow my mind.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/rockefeller.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/rockefeller.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/rockefeller.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/rockefeller.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Selfie @ Rockefeller Center </div> <p>Irene’s friend has a pass that allows her to get free admission to select NY museums so she graciously got us tickets to visit the Museum of Art and Design. If you know me, I’m not the biggest fan of museums (only because I’m very unknowledgable about history) but I thought this museum was nice, although pretty small since some of the exhibits were closed. Afterwards, I tried the famous banana bread pudding from Magnolia Bakery while we people watched in Central Park.</p> <p>A key New York experience is watching a Broadway show and Irene luckily won reduced price tickets to Moulin Rouge. Maybe it was because of the early flight/lack of sleep, but I somehow managed to fall asleep through the entirety of the show… which is actually insane behavior. I literally cannot recall a single thing from that show 😭, literally paid for a nap.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/moulin.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/moulin.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/moulin.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/moulin.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> caught napping </div> <p>We had some time to kill before our reservation at Sushi Hayashi, which is an all-you-can-eat omakase and drinks restaurant. We went on a little walk through the Midtown Manhattan area and visited the NBA store as well. I got a great deal on a Warriors flag for $5, then we chilled at Irene’s apartment for a bit before heading to dinner. I’m able to eat a decent amount, but I think my stomach got smaller because Irene ate more than me. That was also my first omakase experience and I think it was well worth the price, I was SO FULL.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="sunday-323">sunday, 3/23</h4> <ul> <li>Walk across Brooklyn Bridge</li> <li>Dumbo picture spot &amp; Brooklyn Flea Market</li> <li>LOSE ONE AIRPOD</li> <li>Lunch @ Radio Bakery</li> <li>Prospect Park</li> <li>Brooklyn Botanical Gardens</li> <li>Williamsburg and Bushwick</li> <li>Kijitora matcha + Nippon Cha</li> <li>Strand bookstore + Barnes &amp; Noble</li> <li>Dinner @ Soothr</li> </ul> <p>The next day was visiting Brooklyn which started with walking across the Brooklyn Bridge. There were a lot of people going across but after taking our time, we eventually made it to Brooklyn and walked to the numerous photo spots. Along the way, we also stopped by the Brooklyn Flea Market which was interesting, but I was expecting it to be a bit larger.</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/brooklyn-bridge.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/brooklyn-bridge.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/brooklyn-bridge.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/brooklyn-bridge.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/bridge-view.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/bridge-view.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/bridge-view.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/bridge-view.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p>Irene really wanted to go to Radio Bakery for brunch and as we were walking there, we ended up accidentally dropping one of my Airpods into a sewer drain 😭. We weren’t able to retrieve the Airpod but at least Radio Bakery was REALLY REALLY GOOD, definitely worth the wait and price points. I recommend getting the burrata sandwich, that focaccia bread was 👍 to eat in Prospect Park.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/radio.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/radio.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/radio.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/radio.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Burrata sandwich </div> <p>While already in Brooklyn, we visited the Botanical Garden which is large and pretty. We went in late March which is when a majority of the plants are still in dormancy, but we definitely saw the potential of the beauty in the garden.</p> <p>Afterwards, we visited Williamsburg and Bushwick, areas known for thrifting but we didn’t end up getting anything except matcha lattes from Kijitora which Irene guzzled down so fast that she got another one from Nippon Cha. Actually insane behavior</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/matcha.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/matcha.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/matcha.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/matcha.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Irene finished with her first matcha before we even left </div> <p>We had a reservation at Soothr, a really popular Thai restaurant listed on the Michelin Guide, so to kill time, we visited the Strand bookstore and Barnes &amp; Noble. The food ended up being solid and pretty filling, but I don’t think it’s worth the price point.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="monday-324-">monday, 3/24 💻</h4> <ul> <li>Work</li> <li>Lunch from Westville Hudson</li> <li>Hung out with my friend Sashrika</li> </ul> <p>I visited Mercury’s New York office and ate from Westville Hudson for lunch which was okay to eat, but if that was my money, I wouldn’t spend it on that. Afterwards, I hung out with my friend, Sashrika. New York apartments are known for being small but it was only then when I realized how small the apartments actually are… SOOOO SMALL. At least that’s the one perk the Bay Area has over New York, larger apartments for the same price.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="tuesday-325">tuesday, 3/25</h4> <ul> <li>Natural History Museum</li> <li>Lunch @ Chinatown (food crawl)</li> <li>Pier 35 + Two Bridges view</li> <li>Elevated Acre</li> <li>Financial District (+ The Battery)</li> <li>Staten Island Ferry (sunset time)</li> <li>Dinner @ Los Tacos No. 1</li> </ul> <p>I took the day off from work since this was one of Irene’s more free days from school (shout out to Irene again making time for me). First, we visited the Natural History Museum instead of the MET since I’m not the biggest fan of art. The museum was pretty large and you can definitely spend a lot of hours there since there were so many floors. While going through that museum, I was inspired to review my AP World History contents since it’s cool to see how the world has changed throughout time in all different areas/aspects.</p> <p>We were starving so we headed to Chinatown for our food crawl. Flushing is also known for having good Asian food but I wasn’t able to make it fit within this NY visit, but I’ll definitely go there the next time I’m in NY. Here are the places we went and my reviews:</p> <ul> <li>Mei Lei Wah: Pineapple pork bun <ul> <li>Review: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">10/10</code></li> <li>Short line if paying by cash</li> <li>Pineapple pork buns are really warm, juicy, and yummy</li> </ul> </li> <li>Jin Mei Dumpling: 15 dumpies for $5 <ul> <li>Review: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">6/10</code></li> <li>The dumplings we wanted were sold out so we got boiled dumplings instead that honestly weren’t too impressive besides the price</li> </ul> </li> <li>Wah Fung No. 1 Fast Food: Roast pork over rice <ul> <li>Review: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">8/10</code></li> <li>We waited for I think 1.5 hours here and I think there is a lot of value for the price if you end up buying a lot of food. We only got a small rice box to share since we were kind of full, but it was really good and nostalgic. Not too much fat in the roasted pork pieces as well.</li> </ul> </li> <li>Sun Hing Lung: Rice rolls <ul> <li>Review: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">6/10</code></li> <li>Not bad but they were kind of cold</li> </ul> </li> <li>Molly Tea: Authentic tea <ul> <li>Review: <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">8/10</code></li> <li>Really strong tea flavor, and I especially like the design behind the drinking experience (sealed top with another lid over the plastic seal and a small straw to reduce leakage)</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/mei-lah.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/mei-lah.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/mei-lah.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/mei-lah.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Pineapple pork buns from Mei Lah Wah Bakery </div> <p>We brought some of our food crawl haul to eat at Pier 35 while looking at the Two Bridges view. We also waited for ages to sit on the swings at Pier 35. Before boarding the Staten Island Ferry during sunset time, we killed time by visiting the Elevated Acre and walking through a portion of the Financial District. Going on the ferry was a pleasant experience since you get to pass by the Statue of Liberty, but it was a bit chilly with the ocean breeze. To end our day, we ate at Los Tacos No. 1 which was pretty yummy, but I still think that the tacos are a little overpriced.</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/two-bridges.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/two-bridges.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/two-bridges.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/two-bridges.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/statue.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/statue.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/statue.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/statue.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="wednesday-326-">wednesday, 3/26 💻</h4> <ul> <li>Breakfast from Juice Vitality</li> <li>Work</li> <li>Lunch from Thai Diner</li> <li>Dinner @ Cho Dang Gol</li> <li>Walk around Koreatown + Times Square</li> <li>Watch Hadestown</li> </ul> <p>I had work today and we got a surprise acai bowl order from Juice Vitality which was REALLY GOOD since it was actually my first acai bowl and I was so fruit deprived. I also tried Thai Diner for lunch which is supposedly really popular but my DoorDashed order wasn’t very impressive. I left work a tad early to eat at Cho Dang Gol which is a very popular restaurant in Koreatown. The restaurant was full within a few minutes of it opening and the food was definitely very filling and good. I expected Koreatown to be pretty large but it’s actually a small section (like two streets) so we ended up walking through Times Square before our Hadestown show. Irene is the biggest Hadestown fan (she has watched it seven times as of 10/12/2025!!!!!!) and we had booked close seats to have an even better experience watching the show.</p> <p>After seeing how I failed to stay awake while watching Moulin Rouge, I told Irene to slap me if she saw me doze off while watching Hadestown. I was able to stay awake for the first half of the show, and then it kind of went downhill after intermission. There was a sad/quiet scene and Irene said that I made a semi-loud snore sound which received a large side-eye from our seat neighbors… one of the most embarrassing moments of my life. I don’t know, I just fall asleep really easily when watching something, spanning from basketball games which I enjoy to class lectures. I think my attention span is just destroyed after COVID-19 and online learning.</p> <p>Since I only watched half of Hadestown and was awake for some sections of the second half, I felt terrible since I didn’t fully watch the show and it’s Irene’s favorite. In a way, I felt kind of disrespectful and I also am a fan of Greek mythology so this show was interesting to me. After our post-show analysis (which I couldn’t contribute much to), I realized how much I had missed out on and I also was annoyed at how I had spent so much money on another nap. We waited to get autographs from the cast and there was also a group of teenage girls who were so loud and not respectful of others’ spaces which made me very angry.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="thursday-327-">thursday, 3/27 💻</h4> <ul> <li>Work + intern event</li> <li>Lunch from Bondi Sushi + Sunday Morning</li> <li>Shop in Soho area</li> <li>Hung out with my friend Ashley</li> <li>Washington Square Park</li> <li>Dinner @ L’industrie</li> </ul> <p>I had work and ate sushi from Bondi Sushi for lunch, and had ¼ of a cinnamon roll from Sunday Morning. There was also an intern event where I got to meet most of the other interns in-person for the first time, and we made truffles which was pretty cool to learn about and was overall a fun experience.</p> <p>Before meeting up with my friend, Ashley, I shopped in the Soho area at Uniqlo and GU (sister store of Uniqlo). Afterwards, we met up at Washington Square Park and got pizza at L’industrie in West Village. We somehow got two extra slices of pepperoni pieces since they messed up our order lol. I thought the burrata pizza was really good, but the price for a slice is a bit high. Afterwards, we went to Ashley’s apartment which also reaffirmed the smallness of NY apartments.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="friday-328--fake">friday, 3/28 💻 (fake)</h4> <ul> <li>Explore by walking up 5th Avenue (New York Public Library, Grand Central Terminal, Bryant Park, Empire State Building)</li> <li>Lunch from Carrot Express</li> <li>Work half day + interview</li> <li>Madison Square Park</li> <li>Grab standing tickets</li> <li>Dinner @ Joe’s Steamed Rice Roll</li> <li>Watch Hadestown again</li> </ul> <p>This was a fake day of work because I only worked for about half the day. I tried Carrot Express and although it didn’t have the best appearance, it was surprisingly really good. While walking to work, I visited the New York Public Library which looked similar to Doe Library at UC Berkeley. Grand Central Terminal was also along the way which was impressive to see, but I think I would get lost if I was trying to actually navigate through there. Bryant Park and Madison Square Park looked like most of the other parks I visited in New York, and walking up 5th Avenue allowed me to see the Empire State Building which was pretty cool.</p> <p>I was pretty disappointed in myself for sleeping through Hadestown so at work, I searched online on ways to buy discounted/last minute tickets to Broadway shows. Apparently, some shows sell standing tickets for a discounted rate a few hours before the start time and surely if I’m standing, I wouldn’t be able to fall asleep… I told Irene this, and it’s actually crazy how she was down to watch Hadestown again (this was the fifth time I believe). We rushed to get standing tickets and before the show, we ate dinner at Joe’s Steamed Rice Roll near Central Park which was yummy. Also during work this day, I had an interview LOL.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/hadestown.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/hadestown.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/hadestown.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/hadestown.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Hadestown </div> <p>Irene wanted to note down any thoughts/observations she had during the show so we were in search of a pen, which caused us to be almost late to the show so we had to run to get there in time. We were sweating so much but luckily, we made it! I was very proud of myself for not falling asleep throughout the entire show and I definitely recommend watching it. I’ve listened to the soundtrack so many times and definitely know most of the lyrics. It was also funny seeing the amount of notes Irene had written over a page in her Playbill.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="saturday-329">saturday, 3/29</h4> <ul> <li>Central Park</li> <li>Hudson Yards &amp; the Vessel</li> <li>High Line Park</li> <li>Chelsea Market</li> <li>Eat brunch from Apollo Bagels + Veniero’s Pastry @ Pier 57</li> <li>Walk through Little Island</li> <li>Uniqlo</li> <li>Katigiri for quick lunch</li> <li>Flight from JFK to SFO with Irene</li> </ul> <p>Even after days in New York, I hadn’t visited Central Park yet but there were still a few places I needed to visit before leaving. To optimize, the plan was for me to visit Central Park, Hudson Yards &amp; the Vessel and High Line Park before meeting Irene at Chelsea Market where she already picked up goods from Veniero’s Pastry and Apollo Bagels (classic smoked salmon bagel and tomato cream cheese bagel)</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/central-park.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/central-park.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/central-park.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/central-park.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/hudson.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/hudson.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/hudson.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/hudson.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p>We walked to Pier 57 where we ate our haul. I didn’t expect the tomato cream cheese bagel to be that good, but it literally changed both of our lives. IT WAS SO UNEXPECTEDLY DELICIOUS. We were really stuffed so we walked through Little Island to help with digestion, and also picked up an order from Uniqlo before grabbing some food from Katigiri for lunch. It was starting to get hot in New York and while we were riding the tram to Roosevelt Island, there was a mom with pizzas on her stroller and a random guy started singing “mozzarella -ella -ella -ella” which made us both die of laughter. The flight back to the bay was comfortable, but that last day with heat and humidity really made me reconsider on whether I wanted to relocate to New York in the future lol</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/bagels.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/bagels.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/new-york/bagels.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/new-york/bagels.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Haul from Apollo Bagels </div> <h3 id="conclusion">conclusion</h3> <p>New York met all of my expectations of being a place with so many things to do, pricey but in general better tasting food than SF and Seattle, and really small + expensive apartments. I think my lack of friends/acquaintances there makes me the most hesitant towards relocating to NY but I’ll definitely visit there in the future!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="travel"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[first time visiting new yawk 🗽]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">solo in spain</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/solo-in-spain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="solo in spain"/><published>2025-06-28T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-06-28T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/solo-in-spain</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/solo-in-spain/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Note:</strong> I apologize in advance about the slider functionality not working for the images 😔.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="my-itinerary">My Itinerary</h3> <p>I had just graduated from college and this was the most impulsive decision I’ve made so far in my life. Since I was going to be starting work soon and be a corporate cog with limited travel opportunities, I randomly decided that I should travel about two weeks before my start date near the end of June. However, most of my friends are older than me and already working, which meant that it’d be difficult for them to suddenly request time off for a last minute trip.</p> <p>After scouring online for the cheapest country to travel to with the correct time constraints, I decided to go to Barcelona, Spain because I’ve never been there and it was not as hot and humid as other countries. My family doesn’t travel often so finding a new location to go to wasn’t difficult, but I’ve never traveled alone before (aside from Seattle), let alone internationally. However, I was pretty set on traveling so after booking my flight tickets and waiting until the refund period expired, I told my parents that I’d be going to Spain a few days before my flight 😀. I have a Type A personality so I had a set itinerary for each day and time.</p> <p>One thing to note is that Spain is pretty expensive to lodge in, especially after checking the AirBnb and hotel prices. My friend who traveled there previously recommended looking into hostels which was the most affordable option, but I’ve also never stayed in one before so it was definitely a new experience. My Beli also has more detailed food reviews, and feel free to click on each picture to see a zoomed in version as well!</p> <ul> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6/15/2025 - 6/21/2025</li> <li><strong>6/15-6/16:</strong> SF –&gt; Toronto</li> <li><strong>6/16:</strong> Layover in Toronto</li> <li><strong>6/16-6/17:</strong> Toronto –&gt; Barcelona</li> <li><strong>6/17:</strong> Barcelona</li> <li><strong>6/18:</strong> Barcelona</li> <li><strong>6/19:</strong> Barcelona</li> <li><strong>6/20:</strong> Montserrat</li> <li><strong>6/21:</strong> Barcelona –&gt; SF</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="615---617-flights-and-my-first-layover">6/15 - 6/17: flights and my first layover</h4> <ul> <li>Flight from SF to Toronto</li> <li>Layover at Toronto Pearson airport</li> <li>Lunch @ Plaza Premium Terminal 1’s Lounge</li> <li>Interview at the airport</li> <li>Flight from Toronto to Barcelona</li> </ul> <p>I had a red eye flight to Toronto which also included a 12 hour layover. I’ve never had a layover before but after experiencing this one, I do have to admit that it is a little difficult on the body. I also had an interview during my layover which was a weird obstacle to navigate with.</p> <p>I’m probably too privileged with SFO being my closest international airport, but my initial plan was to do the interview in an empty gate which likely wouldn’t be hard to find, especially since airports are generally large and quiet. After searching online and browsing through Reddit, Toronto Pearson airport is notorious for not being the greatest airport since it’s generally loud. Therefore, I looked into airport lounges but even the airport lounges had terrible reviews. I found a promotion code online which gave me 30% off and decided to book a few hours in the lounge just in case, and I’d also get “free” food.</p> <p>After walking through the airport, it was clear that I wouldn’t be able to find an empty gate to do my interview in since the airport was somewhat small. My flight was departing from Terminal 1, but I had booked the lounge in Terminal 3 because it mentioned online that there was a private room. Turns out, the terminals in this airport are only connected through an airbus which you can only access if you haven’t gone through security. Additionally, the airport attendants said that I wouldn’t even be able to enter that terminal unless my flight departed from there…</p> <p>I panicked and called the lounge to see if there was any way to transfer my booking, and after an hour they were luckily able to 🙏. Leading up to the interview, my plans were to prepare a bit, but honestly I was so tired from the flight since I had a middle seat the flight before. I also lost one of the foam pieces for my noise-canceling earbuds which was so tragic. The Plaza Premium Lounge in Terminal 1 is just like what the online reviews say. It was terrible, small, crowded, loud, and the food was pretty bad – definitely not recommended. As a result, I had to try to find an empty gate which I was able to, and did my interview on the ground. The airport wifi was horrendous so I had to connect to my personal hotspot. Unfortunately near the end of the interview, people started coming to the gate which ended up causing a lot of background noise and people were looking at me weirdly since I was sitting on the ground. At least during my flight to Barcelona, I had an aisle seat and was sitting next to a nice elderly man so there weren’t any problems. I did try to watch Wicked but I fell asleep twice and still didn’t end up finishing the movie during the 8 hour flight 💀</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/lounge.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/lounge.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/lounge.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/lounge.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/lounge-selfie.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/lounge-selfie.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/lounge-selfie.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/lounge-selfie.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="617-barcelona">6/17: Barcelona</h4> <p><strong>Step Count:</strong> 28,000+</p> <ul> <li>Breakfast: Airplane food</li> <li>La Rambla</li> <li>Lunch @ La Boqueria: Watermelon slices + ham &amp; cheese empanada</li> <li>Pier + mall</li> <li>Checked into hostel</li> <li>Snack @ Hofmann Pastisseria: Croissant</li> <li>Casa Batlló</li> <li>Dinner @ Cervecería Catalana: Tapas</li> </ul> <p>My flight landed in the morning and in order to get to my hostel (St Christopher’s Inn Barcelona ), I took the Aerobús which is Barcelona’s official transportation to get to and from the airport. The Aerobús dropped me off close to my hostel, but I still needed to take an additional bus ride which is when I bought the <a href="https://www.tmb.cat/en/barcelona-fares-metro-bus/t-casual">T-casual ticket</a> at a transit station. Before this trip, I didn’t know how severe the pickpocket scene was in Europe, especially in transit stations which is why I was extremely cautious throughout this entire trip. Luckily, I didn’t get pickpocketed throughout the trip.</p> <blockquote> <p>T-casual Barcelona Metro Bus ticket provides 10 trips within one zone (which covers most of Barcelona) for €12.55.</p> </blockquote> <p>My check-in time for the hostel was at 3 PM so I had a couple of hours to explore beforehand. I walked to Mercat de la Boqueria (La Boqueria) since it was pretty close and I was a bit hungry after my flight. I was <strong>EXTREMELY SHOCKED</strong> to discover that Spain drinks a lot of juice/smoothies, in addition to having a lot of fruit stands. I was literally in heaven because if you know me, I have dreams of buying an expensive blender and making smoothies + acai bowls in the future. After walking around the market, I decided to buy a cup of watermelon slices since my throat wasn’t feeling too well (if you know, watermelon combats the yeet hay) and a ham &amp; cheese empanada. The market reminded me of Nishiki Market in Kyoto, Japan except for selling juice/fruit + deli meats instead of Japanese street foods + fish. I went to a nearby plaza to eat and while there, I watched a seagull eat another dead seagull… that was the day I learned that seagulls are carnivorous.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/juice.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/juice.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/juice.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/juice.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Cups of watermelon + juice! </div> <p>After lunch, I walked around La Rambla which is essentially a long street down to Mirador de Colom (Colombus Monument). Then, I walked to Port Vell and checked out Maremagnum, which is a mall with air conditioning because it was so hot. The Balearic Sea water was extremely turquoise and pretty with fish swimming in it, but the mall was pretty standard.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/pier.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/pier.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/pier.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/pier.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <p>Nearing my check-in time, I walked back to my hostel where I was blessed with a bottom bunk bed. I brought a padlock to secure my belongings and it was then when I realized that Europe has different outlet ports than America. With my hostel room type (12 girls + shared bathrooms), I thought that I’d be provided with a towel but apparently that wasn’t true in the fine print. I also realized that there wasn’t any water available for refill at the hostel. Aside from that, the hostel reminded me a lot of living in the college dorms and the overall experience staying there wasn’t bad for being the cheapest living option as a solo traveler.</p> <p>The main thing on the agenda today was my visit to Casa Batlló in the evening. After rotting in my room for a bit, I walked through La Rambla again and up Passeig de Gràcia. Near the El Born area was a famous bakery called Hofmann Pastisseria which was where I bought a croissant to eat while I walked to Casa Batlló. To my disappointment, it tasted pretty similar to a Costco croissant.</p> <p>When planning my itinerary, I was choosing between visiting Casa Batlló, Casa Milà, or both. I decided on only visiting Casa Batlló since tickets were a bit pricey and the same architect designed both houses. Afternoon tickets to Casa Batlló included a free cava drink which honestly wasn’t that bad, but I cannot hold any alcohol so after taking a sip, I handed the full glass right back to the server 😀. The rest of the house was pretty interesting and cool to experience in-person. The audio tour was also a new experience I enjoyed because I got to look at different pieces/areas at my own pace.</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-1.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-1.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-1.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-1.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-2.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-2.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-2.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-2.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-3.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-3.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-3.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-3.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-4.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-4.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-4.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/casa-batllo-4.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p>After an hour at Casa Batlló (new record for me), I was hungry and decided to go to Cervecería Catalana because it was highly recommended by my friend’s parents alongside ChatGPT. There was a pretty long line but since I was alone, I got seated immediately at the bar. This was my first time eating tapas which are basically a bunch of side dishes one can choose from. I didn’t really know what to order so I just ordered items from the “popular” section of the menu. Everything was really yummy and the food tasted very luxurious. Best of all, the total price didn’t hurt my wallet even though I also ordered a dessert! Definitely my favorite restaurant that I tried during this trip.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/cc.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/cc.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/cc.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/cc.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Two tapas (mini hamburger and this steak thing) </div> <p>I desperately needed to go on an errands run because I needed to buy an adapter to charge my devices and a water jug. The adapter was kind of expensive ($11) but it was essential… the 5 liter water jug also was a great purchase.</p> <p>The toilet paper also came out of a strange towel-like dispenser which caused the paper to be pretty scrunched up. The hostel is right next to Plaça de Catalunya so I walked through that plaza a lot. At the end of the day, I ended with over 26,000 steps and went to sleep really early after taking a great shower.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="618-barcelona">6/18: Barcelona</h4> <p><strong>Step Count:</strong> 25,000+</p> <ul> <li>Brunch @ Chök Carme: Brookie</li> <li>Montjuïc Hill</li> <li>Barceloneta Beach</li> <li>Snack @ Gelati Dino: Mint + cookie crumble cone</li> <li>Gothic Quarter</li> <li>Dinner @ Bodega del Born: Tapas</li> <li>Dessert @ Xurreria Laietana: Chocolate dipped churros</li> </ul> <p>This was the first full day in Barcelona which I started off by grabbing a pastry from Chök Carme. I got their most famous item, a brookie, which I thought was pretty good but it’s definitely a bit heavy and should be shared amongst more people.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/brookie.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/brookie.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/brookie.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/brookie.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Brookie </div> <p>Next was exploring Montjuïc Hill which I got to by taking the bus up there. Unfortunately, I had an oopsie with where to get off of and I also scanned my T-casual ticket incorrectly so in panic, I used Apple Pay to pay for the bus ride which ended up being $16 for some reason 🤡.</p> <p>There are two cable cars related to the hill and I had a reservation for the cable car down to Barceloneta Beach (Transbordador Aeri del Port). When riding the bus, we passed by a stop that mentioned a cable car so I thought I needed to ride that in order to get up the hill (as opposed to hiking up the hill), but turns out riding that cable car wasn’t necessary. That cable car was Telefèric de Montjuïc (Montjuïc Cable Car) which was a scenic ride up to the hill, but definitely not needed if you’re already taking the bus up there because the walk up to Montjuïc Castle is fairly short and not strenuous.</p> <p>Additionally, I thought that I needed to get to my reservation for the cable car to the beach by 1 PM so I thought that I only had time for the castle. I explored it quickly just to realize that my reservation didn’t have a time specified… I could use that ticket for the entire day…</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle-2.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle-2.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle-2.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle-2.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle-3.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle-3.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle-3.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/castle-3.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p>It was so hot so after cooling down for a bit, I rode down the mountain on the cable car. It was scenic since the route was going from the hill down towards the beach, and the water was really turquoise. I planned on trying paella at the beach but honestly, I wasn’t really hungry and it was around 3 PM so I decided to get gelato instead. I went to Gelati Dino which was good, but I wasn’t particularly impressed.</p> <p>Barceloneta Beach was also fairly standard but since I didn’t bring a swimsuit, I didn’t swim. After chilling at the beach, I explored the Gothic Quarter and the Cathedral of Santa Eulàlia (Barcelona Cathedral) which was jaw dropping. I kind of just walked around Gothic Quarter so I’m not too sure what I exactly saw, but here are the ones I know I for sure visited:</p> <ul> <li>The Roman Walls</li> <li>Plaça de Sant Jaume</li> <li>Temple of Augustus</li> <li>Plaça del Rei</li> <li>Palau Reial Major</li> <li>Palatine Chapel of Sant Agata</li> <li>Palau del Lloctinent</li> <li>Plaça Nova</li> <li>Archdeacon House</li> <li>Bishop’s Bridge (Pont del Bisbe)</li> <li>Sant Felip Neri Square</li> <li>Jewish Quarter (El Call)</li> <li>Synagogue Major</li> <li>Human Pyramids Monument</li> <li>Basílica dels Sants Just i Pastor</li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/cathedral.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/cathedral.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/cathedral.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/cathedral.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Cathedral </div> <p>For dinner and dessert, I went to Bodega del Born which is a traditional tapas location and Xurreria Laietana for chocolate dipped churros. Both were pretty good (churros were kind of yeet hay) and I sat at Plaça de Catalunya eating the churros while watching the sunset. One thing to note is that most restaurants in Spain kind of expect you to drink and since I get terrible asian glow, I always asked for water which I thought was free, but turned out to have a cost lol. I tried an anchovy dish and it was surprisingly pretty good.</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/gelato.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/gelato.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/gelato.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/gelato.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/bodega.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/bodega.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/bodega.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/bodega.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="619-barcelona">6/19: Barcelona</h4> <p><strong>Step Count:</strong> 20,000+</p> <ul> <li>Breakfast @ Juice Dudes: Smoothie</li> <li>Park Güell</li> <li>Sagrada Família</li> <li>Dinner @ The famous Bar: Seafood paella</li> </ul> <p>I had a late start this day because the other people in my room were packing up to leave so I didn’t want to step outside of my bunk. Once they left, I got ready and went to Juice Dudes for a smoothie since it was along the way. After looking at the price now, I don’t think the smoothie is worth it but it was really good haha. The main items on this day’s itinerary were Park Güell and Basílica de la Sagrada Família later in the day. A couple of Gràcia’s plazas were along the way to Park Güell so I stopped by Plaça de la Vila de Gràcia and Plaça del Sol. It was about 90°F so I needed to sit in the shade for a while before going on the bus to Park Güell. After arriving there, I sat in the shade again because my entry time into the park wasn’t until 1.5 hours and it was so hot.</p> <p>I didn’t realize that I needed to download the app and audio guide prior to entering the park but the data there was terrible so I wasn’t able to. I just explored the park at my own leisure and it was definitely really pretty, but I wasn’t extremely impressed with anything in particular. The views were nice, but I was anticiapting more elaborate buildings. I didn’t get to see everything in the park due to time and temperature constraints, but I still think it was a cool place to visit.</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-1.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-1.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-1.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-1.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-2.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-2.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-2.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-2.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-3.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-3.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-3.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-3.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-4.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-4.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-4.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-4.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-5.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-5.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-5.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park-guell-5.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p>Afterwards, I walked down from the park to the Sagrada Família. I was so hungry that during the walk, I mistook some images on an OBGYN office as gelato flavors… At the Sagrada Família, I also needed to download their app and audio guide which I was luckily able to do since there was public WiFi. I had to listen to the express version but I thought this attraction was especially intricate and fascinating… I wish I was able to spend more time there.</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada-2.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada-2.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada-2.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada-2.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada-3.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada-3.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada-3.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/sagrada-3.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p>I needed to try paella so I went to The famous Bar because it was close by and decently rated. To my surprise, there were a lot of asian people dining at the restaurant. I couldn’t read the menu and my data wasn’t working so I ordered something that looked like seafood paella. It was pretty good but definitely a bit heavy. After the meal, I went back to my hostel, showered, and went to sleep.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="620-montserrat">6/20: Montserrat</h4> <p><strong>Step Count:</strong> ~18,000</p> <ul> <li>Brunch @ Oakberry: Açaí bowl</li> <li>Montserrat</li> <li>Arc de Triomf</li> <li>Parc de la Ciutadella</li> <li>Dinner @ La Xampanyeria</li> <li>Pooped</li> </ul> <p>Another late start to this day and since it was so hot (over 90°F), I was pretty unmotivated to go to Montserrat because it’s even hotter there. After getting my açaí bowl from Oakberry, I decided to still go because I shouldn’t be moping around while in a new country. The acai bowl was good but after looking at what I paid for it, it’s definitely not worth it.</p> <p>The article called “Train Journey Barcelona to Montserrat” from Barcelona Tourist Guide is very informative on how to get to Montserrat from Barcelona and it’s definitely tricky to navigate around. There are mainly two ticket packages to choose from for Montserrat and I chose the Trans Montserrat ticket because it included all of the tickets I needed. It was ~$50 which isn’t bad, but I think it’s cheaper if you buy the tickets individually.</p> <p>The train to Montserrat was about an hour long but thankfully, there was air conditioning on it. To get up to Montserrat, you can choose between the cable car or railway option. I chose the cable car option because it’s more scenic, but I didn’t read the article closely enough and apparently, you have to depart one stop earlier than what Google Map recommends in order to get on the cable car… I didn’t do this so I had to spend ~$10 more to get on the railway because otherwise, I’d have to wait an hour for the train to come back in the opposite direction. The railway was good because there was air conditioning and the views from the railway were particularly scenic since the route up to Montserrat was basically around the mountain.</p> <p>Once at the top, I walked around and the views were pretty insane. It was really hot though so to cool down, I loitered around in the gift shop and food areas. Inside the monastery was the basilica which I bought tickets to right outside the entrance. The WiFi at Montserrat was actually decent so I was able to download the app and audio guide. I decided to skip out on the museum and Black Madonna because I’m not the biggest fan of museums and I had missed the Boys’ Choir performance which is at 1 PM.</p> <p>The basilica was interesting to walk through and afterwards, I walked through some nature areas which lead to the hikes up to the peaks. It was way too hot to hike though so after eating my protein bar for lunch, I rode the Sant Joan funicular which leads up to the top of Montserrat mountain. The views were even better up from there. There’s another funicular which I thought I’d be able to take after the Sant Joan one, but I think it’s actually at the base of the mountain? Still not sure where that funicular is…</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-1.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-1.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-1.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-1.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-2.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-2.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-2.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-2.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-3.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-3.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-3.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/montserrat-3.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p>Around 4pm, I decided to head back to Barcelona since I had finished exploring Montserrat. I was able to find the cable car down to the train station and it was a good experience seeing the views as we descended, plus there was a nice breeze. The train back to Barcelona was the same but it was a bit more crowded and hot.</p> <p>I got back to Barcelona around 6 PM and decided to go to Arc de Triomf and Parc de la Ciutadella since I wasn’t able to visit those areas during previous days. The Arc was very intricate, and the park was really big – it reminded me a lot of Central Park in New York since there was a zoo there as well. I only got to walk through about 1/4th of the park before deciding to head out to eat because I was really hungry. I ate at Can Paixano, aka La Xampanyeria, which is a traditional bar serving tapas. The other day, I walked past the restaurant and the line was insane which is why I didn’t eat there but today, I arrived when the line wasn’t as outrageous so I waited in line. Honestly, I thought the food was fine but a bit pricey so I wasn’t as satisfied.</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/arc.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/arc.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/arc.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/arc.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/barcelona/park.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p>Up till now, I hadn’t pooped since leaving SF (Sunday) because the toilet paper came out so scrunched. I didn’t really have a need to poop until yesterday, and it was all I could think about from Wednesday to Friday (today). My flight was the next day so I thought that I had come so far, I should just extend the streak of not pooping since it was just one more day. Unfortunately, every instance of me eating fruit triggered the desire to poop because of the fiber. Additionally, walking was one step closer to pooping in my pants so once I arrived back at my hostel, I pooped for the first time since Sunday. I was unsuccessful in my challenge of not pooping throughout my trip but at least, I was able to extend my streak of days gone without pooping to five days.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="621-barcelona--sf">6/21: Barcelona –&gt; SF</h4> <ul> <li>Souvenir shopping</li> <li>Brunch @ Honest Greens: Breakfast tostada</li> <li>More souvenir shopping</li> <li>Airport</li> </ul> <p>Before my flight, I needed to bring back at least some souvenirs for my family and friends since I didn’t do that for my past few trips. My check out time was at 11 AM which I thought would be ample time to search for souvenirs but I forgot to factor in that those stores wouldn’t be open that early in the day. It ended up being a pretty unsuccessful run so I went back to my hostel, packed up my belongings and checked out. For brunch, I ate at Honest Greens which provided the most satisfaction and affordability out of all the places I dined at.</p> <p>I still didn’t have any gifts purchased so I walked around for a bit on La Rambla trying to find gift shops that didn’t look too suspicious. Despite more gift shops opening up, I couldn’t find anything I really liked so I bought turróns which is a traditional Spanish nougat. At the shop, I asked a worker if they had any without nuts since my sister is allergic to them, and the worker looked at me in disbelief because basically 90% of turróns contain almonds.</p> <p>I spent a bit more time than anticipated trying to find souvenirs so due to the time constraints, I had to hastily board the bus back to the airport. One thing I noticed was how security seemed pretty lax at the airport. I didn’t see a single bag get stopped at security and there were very few workers checking bodies compared to TSA in America.</p> <p>Thankfully, I had a direct flight back to SFO through United Airlines and I was pleasantly surprised with the experience: a neck pillow was provided, there were so many drink/snack refills, and the food was pretty good. I was sitting at the very last row of the plane because I didn’t want a middle seat, but the person next to me was pretty annoying to sit next to because they kept getting into my personal space and touching me. The flight was also extremely turbulent to the point where my cup of orange juice spilled onto my lap and seat… Typically, I don’t watch a lot of shows/movies but during this flight, I ended up finishing Wicked, Joker: Folie à Deux, Grave of the Fireflies, and part of Kiki’s Delivery Service. Grave of the Fireflies was an insane movie to watch on the plane and I needed to take some time to reflect afterwards.</p> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="fin">fin</h3> <p>Overall, my wallet hurt a bit after this spontaneous trip but I’m glad that I decided to go because I won’t have many more opportunities to travel without needing to take PTO.</p> <p>Some takeaways are:</p> <ol> <li>I don’t recommend going to Spain during the summer because of the heat, but the architecture is definitely very beautiful.</li> <li>The conversion rate between 1 USD and 1 Euro isn’t the best. Additionally, don’t exchange for paper money at the airport because everything uses contactless payment…</li> <li>Europe uses Type F outlets.</li> <li>It depends on the person but I think three or four days in Barcelona is the perfect amount of time to see the touristy sites in the area without getting bored.</li> <li>Solo traveling provides a lot of freedom but it does get lonesome sometimes. All of my pictures are 0.5 selfies with my facial expression being 😐 haha</li> </ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="travel"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[first time solo-traveling and in europe]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">how i almost died while hiking</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/how-i-almost-died-while-hiking/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="how i almost died while hiking"/><published>2025-01-13T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-13T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/how-i-almost-died-while-hiking</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/how-i-almost-died-while-hiking/"><![CDATA[<p>Seattle. <em>What is Seattle known for?</em> Most people immediately think of constant rain and tech bros. While those assumptions are kind of true, Seattle is also part of the Pacific Northwest, a great location for nature activities (see here for <a href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-PNW-hikes/">my reviews</a> on some PNW hikes).</p> <p>During my first summer in Seattle, I went on my first hike and almost died becuase I was a noob and knew nothing. Let’s recall the tale…</p> <p>I had three other close friends in Seattle and it was our second and third weeks here, meaning that we were due to go on a hike. One friend typically planned our hangouts because they were the “planner friend”, so they chose a hike to go on. We also had a strange idea of eating a coconut at the peak of the hike while chugging Truly Hard Seltzers because one of us had never tried coconut before. For the record, we were all underage at the time 🙂‍↕️ (<em>shhh</em>)</p> <p>There’s an affordable bus system called the Trailhead Direct which has shuttles that drop riders off to some trailheads. We planned to meet at the stop outside Seattle Public Library – Central Library at 9:30 AM. I woke up a bit late so I didn’t eat breakfast and while rushing out of the door, I hastily grabbed my water bottle and a Rice Krispy treat. I don’t know why I didn’t think to eat before hiking or at least bringing snacks… <strong>NOOB</strong></p> <p>By the time all of us arrived at the stop, it was starting to drizzle but we didn’t think too much of it since the weather forecast said that it’d stop soon. However, the shuttle that was supposed to come didn’t show up. We were puzzled and confused if we somehow were at the wrong spot. There were a few other hikers at the stop so we were certain that we went to the correct location, but the shuttle still wasn’t there and it comes every hour. The other hikers were still waiting so we decided to wait as well, hoping that the shuttle would come soon.</p> <p>However, it started raining harder and the shuttle was late again. We considered walking to a different shuttle stop in case the stop we were at was no longer active, but after about three hours from our original meeting time, the shuttle <strong>FINALLY</strong> arrived past noon. We boarded the shuttle (which was extremely packed) and were on our one hour journey to the trailhead.</p> <p>Once we arrived at the trailhead, we started ascending. My friend had mentioned which trail we were going on but to be honest, I didn’t really pay attention since I was sleepy and just followed them while they were navigating. As a result, I didn’t know how long the route was.</p> <p>Turns out, we were hiking Teneriffe Falls Trail which is ranked <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Hard</code> on <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/trail/us/washington/teneriffe-falls">AllTrails</a> and is 5.7 miles with 1,620 feet elevation gain. Additionally, the trail was very muddy because of the rain, and since this was my first time hiking, I was only wearing an old pair of tennis shoes which had zero grip. The overall scenery kind of looked like something out of <em>The Twilight Saga</em>.</p> <p>At that time, I was probably also at one of my most unfit stages of my life so I was huffing and puffing, alongside asthma. We took breaks while hiking where I conservatively drank my water. Nearing the top of the mountain, it started becoming <strong>EXTREMELY</strong> rocky (see the reviews on AllTrails). It was a little scary bouldering across the wet rocks with slippery shoes but eventually, we made it past that obstacle. Going up those rocks was so much easier than going down.</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-rocks.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-rocks.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-rocks.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-rocks.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-twilight.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-twilight.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-twilight.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-twilight.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p>At some point, my friend suddenly said that we finished. I looked around and we weren’t even at a peak with a view, which is what I was expecting. All I saw in front of me was a waterfall with a small flow rate. It was at that moment where I realized seeing the waterfall was the “peak” of the summit. Bruh.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="max-width: 450px; margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Teneriffe Falls </div> <p>I was kind of peeved because we had just gone on that strenuous hike <strong>FOR THAT</strong>? There wasn’t even a safe platform/edge to be near the waterfall since the edge we were on was pretty small with trees in front of us. To get more space, we (stupidly) decided to cross the river which was a good distance below our current location. At that point, I was pretty tired and one fun fact about me is that I outbreak in hives at random occurrences. This ended up being one of those times 🤡 and I could feel the hives spreading throughout my body.</p> <p>After crossing the river and to celebrate us reaching the “top” of the hike, we decided to crack open our coconut and drinks. We quite literally went “caveman-style” and smashed the coconut on rocks to open it. Fun fact: It’s hard to open coconuts without a knife. Three of us attempted splitting the coconut evenly but it was pretty unsuccessful so we gave up and started nibbling it. The coconut ended up being the second worst coconut I’ve ever eaten — the coconut was unripe causing it to not be sweet and the flesh was extremely hard to separate from the coconut shell.</p> <div class="d-flex justify-content-center"> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true" style="max-width: 450px;"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-solo.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-solo.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-solo.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-solo.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> </div> <p>We lugged up all of our alcoholic beverages to the top so obviously, we needed to start drinking them. If you don’t know me, I’m a lightweight and get “asian flush” literally after a sip of alcohol. Since my stomach was completely empty, I needed to fill it up with some substance so I ate my Rice Krispy treat and chugged my Truly. Immediately after, I started turning red and could feel myself getting a really bad headache but I had no medicine, food, and very little water left. The idea itself arguably isn’t that dumb but I should have known to not drink since I’m a lightweight and had no food. However, I didn’t want to be a party pooper which is why I ended up doing it.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <div style="margin: auto; text-align: center;"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-cheers-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-cheers-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-cheers-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/teneriffe/teneriffe-cheers.gif" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1 w-50" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Cheers </div> <p>After we finished our break at the top and took pictures, we started descending the mountain. My headache had marinated and was in full blossom, continuously pounding like a metronome set at 120 BPM. We barely started moving but I was out of water. It was <strong>SO SCARY</strong> descending the rocky area because I was lightheaded and dizzy, but after taking it really slow, I was able to make it through.</p> <p>I didn’t tell my friends how unwell I was feeling because I didn’t want to seem “weak” in front of them (which in hindsight is also so dumb). There were some instances where two of them were racing each other on flatter paths and because I was taking things slow, I made our descent down slightly longer than the time it took for us to ascend the mountain. Once we finally reached the bottom, I wanted to throw up so badly even though I ate very little. After using the disgusting Porta Potty and resting for 20 minutes, I felt a lot better and more calm. The alcohol wore off and my heart rate was a lot slower, but my headache was still terrible. We rode another shuttle back for an hour where I passed out and afterwards ate a nice big bowl of ramen.</p> <p>After 15+ hikes in Seattle, I look back at this time as one of those core memories you do when you’re just a goofy young adult with your friends having fun. I literally don’t know if my brain was even present that day because every single action was <strong>TERRIBLE</strong> but at least, I have a funny story to tell 💀</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="reflections"/><category term="travel"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[my first hike]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">my first semester as a TA</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/takeaways-from-ta/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="my first semester as a TA"/><published>2025-01-11T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-11T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/takeaways-from-ta</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/takeaways-from-ta/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>DISCLAIMER:</strong> These are the thoughts and opinions from one student after teaching two data science classes at UC Berkeley.</p> <hr/> <p>Being part of course staff has been one of my most valuable experiences as an undergraduate student. After the Fall 2024 semester, I wanted to share the lessons I’ve learned and things I’ve discovered as a first time teaching assistant (TA).</p> <p>Before that, I wanted to outline the process it took for me to become part of course staff. At Berkeley, there’s a lot of demand for being part of course staff and everyone’s journey to joining is different. The most general and straightforward approach is first being an academic intern (AI), tutor/reader, then teaching assistant. The course staff positions available also depend on the EE/CS/DS course since some courses might not have academic interns.</p> <p>These are the positions I held as part of course staff:</p> <ul> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring 2022</code>: Data 8 Academic Intern</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Summer 2022</code>: CS 61B(L) Academic Intern</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Fall 2022</code>: CS 61A Academic Intern</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Fall 2023</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Tutor</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring 2024</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Tutor</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Fall 2024</code>: Data 101 Teaching Assistant</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring 2025</code>: Data 101 Head Teaching Assistant</li> </ul> <p>These are the positions I held as part of <a href="https://csmentors.studentorg.berkeley.edu/#/">Computer Science Mentors (CSM)</a> @ Berkeley where I taught weekly tutoring sections for a group of 4-5 students:</p> <ul> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Fall 2022</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Junior Mentor</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring 2023</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Senior Mentor</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Fall 2023</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Senior Mentor</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring 2024</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Senior Mentor</li> </ul> <p>Prior to getting those positions, I was continuously rejected from course staff until I eventually gained more experience and refined my application. Even though I’ve spent almost every semester teaching, I still have <strong>SO MUCH</strong> to improve on. There have been multiple instances where I didn’t know the answer to a student’s question or stumbled when mini-lecturing, but that’s a reason why I continue to teach — so I can continue improving as an instructor and help others learn.</p> <p>When transitioning from being a tutor to a TA, I thought that there wouldn’t be too big of a change with the exception of running my own discussion section individually. However, there were a lot of differences that I didn’t anticipate. As a disclaimer, these are five takeaways from one student after teaching two data science classes at Berkeley.</p> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="1-exam-logistics-are-a-lot-of-work">1. Exam logistics are a lot of work</h2> <p>Teaching assistants usually have a focus area, such as proofreading discussion worksheets, labs, projects, etc. My focus area was admin/logistics, meaning that I was in charge of managing weekly announcements, course email inbox, all exam logistics (room/seating assignments for students, staff proctoring and grading logistics, exam review sessions) for midterm and final exams, feedback forms, and the basic TA duties of teaching + office hours.</p> <p>Prior to being a Logistics TA, I never knew how much work went into holding an exam. At Berkeley, typically the week or a few days before an exam, students will receive an email stating their assigned room location and optionally, their assigned seat. I never thought too much about that email but the process it takes to book exam rooms, accommodate exam preferences (ex: left-handed seats), assign seats, etc is extremely lengthy and time consuming. When running exams, regular and DSP (<a href="https://dsp.berkeley.edu/home">Disabled Students’ Program</a>) students need to be accounted for and there’s additional logistics to account for if there are alternate exams. And that’s just for holding the exam, not to mention exam review sessions, writing the exam (dependent on course), and grading the exam…</p> <p>I remember spending hours on exam logistics and quite literally manually assigning 200 students’ seats because we didn’t have enough seats from the exam rooms provided, causing the Seating Tool to not work effectively.</p> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="2-student-support-is-important">2. Student support is important</h2> <p>Throughout the semester, since I was monitoring the staff email inbox, I categorized which emails pertained to which TA. There were hundreds of emails requesting for additional student support because of personal issues and even more leading up to exams or deadlines. Before this, I never knew how many students contacted course staff and the answer is, hundreds.</p> <p>There’s a lot of variance between courses on the extent of support from course staff. Typically, there’s a lot less or none for upper division courses because students are expected to be able to handle the rigor. However, I personally believe that there should always be student support in any course because unexpected circumstances occur out of one’s control and it’s a lot to handle while balancing school. Depending on the circumstances, it’s sometimes okay for a course to be less accommodating but generally, I believe that it’s best practice to thoroughly evaluate the scenario before arriving at a conclusion.</p> <p>For courses that provide student support, it takes up a lot more time than you think. Typically, each student that requires support results in multiple student support meetings that range from 15 min to hour long meetings, then you have to multiply that for every single student that wants or needs additional support. This especially builds up around exams or deadlines which takes up a lot of time for the student support TA.</p> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="3-established-vs-developing-courses">3. Established vs. developing courses</h2> <p>The first course I taught was <a href="https://c88c.org/fa23/">CS 88 / Data C88C</a>, which is the lower division fundamentals data science course that is built on top of CS 61A, an even older course. The next course I taught was <a href="https://data101.org/fa24/">Data 101</a>, which is the upper division data engineering course. Data 101 has only been offered for five semesters as of Spring 2025, meaning that the course changes every semester (for improvements) in comparison to CS 88 rarely changing.</p> <p>With all of the changes, course staff needs to be able to adapt to additional content being added. I remember some instances where the students and I were learning at the same time, except I also needed to be able to teach it during my own discussion section.</p> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="4-teaching-lower-division-vs-upper-division-courses">4. Teaching lower division vs. upper division courses</h2> <p>Adding on to the differences between teaching CS 88 and Data 101, the largest takeaway is probably the type of students I taught. In lower division courses, students are a lot less knowledgeable so there are a lot more “basic” questions, especially since CS 88 is an introduction to programming. However, in upper division courses, students are more familiar with programming and ask more conceptual-based questions that I sometimes didn’t know the answer to. Additionally, I typically didn’t know the students I taught in CS 88 since lower classmen (freshman, sophomores) took that class whereas in Data 101, I taught students that I knew or shared classes with which was sometimes weird. For instance, it puts staff in a weird position if students ask for help through Instagram direct messages…</p> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="5-cs-education-is-intriguing">5. CS education is intriguing</h2> <p>Not much more to it. I never enjoyed or found research too interesting but especially after TAing, it’s an avenue I want to dive deeper into.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="opinions"/><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[some takeaways]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">christmas</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/christmas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="christmas"/><published>2025-01-10T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-10T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/christmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/christmas/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <p>Everyone has different traditions and activities so here is how my family does Christmas, alongside my thoughts. I also want to preface this post with it being entirely a rant and my own opinions/perspectives since I know I’m extremely privileged and grateful to be able to even have the luxury to relax during the holidays.</p> <p>Looking back, I can only recall my family decorating and putting up a Christmas tree three times, all occurrences before entering middle school. There were probably a few more instances of the tree being put up when I was really little but I don’t really remember those times. My family isn’t Christian but Christmas is such a global holiday that most people celebrate it, especially given its presence in various media forms (ex: books, movies, shows, etc).</p> <p><em>So, why doesn’t my family celebrate Christmas?</em></p> <p>I think the main reason is because my parents never celebrated it growing up either. Since they immigrated to America during their teenage years, they didn’t get much exposure to those festivities while trying to make ends meet.</p> <p>Once they got older and learned more about the culture, they tried integrating aspects of it when raising my siblings and I by mainly putting up a Christmas tree. Since we infrequently put up the Christmas tree, I literally only remember decorating it three times and always getting excited to see the darkness being illuminated by the tree’s lights — it made me feel comfy and I just liked being near the tree. Personally, I think that this doesn’t reinforce the main takeaways of Christmas such as being able to spend time with family and learning how to be selfless.</p> <p>As a child, I remember only thinking about what presents I would get. I would only get one gift from my parents and they always prefaced it with “you can choose whatever you want as long as it’s not too expensive”. With that reasoning, I never believed in Santa Claus because my parents never did activities such as snowy footprints to pretend that Santa dropped off presents under our tree. My house also doesn’t have a chimney so… there’s that haha</p> <p>As a teenager, Christmas still revolved around presents. My family is disjoint from both sides of the family so we never had a lot of presents in the first place or family gatherings, usually just presents from my parents and our cousins that are close in age. However, my parents started a newer tradition of going to Lake Tahoe with our cousins during winter break since we had all never been before. This allowed us to have more family time and therefore marked the end of us putting up the Christmas tree since we had stopped for a couple of years. Going to Lake Tahoe is always special to me because it’s the only vacation that my family goes on since we don’t travel much. I remember always being excited the night before leaving and being in awe when seeing snow.</p> <p>With the pandemic occurring and college applications rolling around in 2019, my family stopped going to Tahoe. Winter break became a time for me to initially rest, then grind during high school and college.</p> <p>Especially with extended family arguments, Christmas is just an ordinary day during winter break for my family and I. There is no Christmas tree, Christmas presents, Tahoe trip, or family gatherings. Whenever I receive text messages from friends wishing me “Merry Christmas” or “Happy New Year”, it always makes me feel weird (in some sense) since my family doesn’t celebrate those holidays.</p> <p>As I’ve grown older, presents hold less value and seeing various traditions on social media sometimes made me a bit envious of how close people are to their family and friends. Children experiencing the magic of Christmas is an event that can only happen once in a lifetime before it gets ruined. Even playing silly holiday games or participating in White Elephant seems so fun. Perhaps my siblings and I can be the change once we’re older and establish new traditions.</p> <p>My dad denoted this Christmas as the “worst Christmas ever” because my grandma suffered from a stroke a few days prior, causing her to be hospitalized for three weeks as of this post. Spending Christmas and in general, a lot of time at the hospital was a very impactful experience for me and allowed me to truly reflect about the time we have alive. It made me feel so sad to see patients helpless, trying their best to get healthy. Additionally, hospital workers have to deal with so much emotional baggage with each patient they interact with. I’m not going to go more into specifics but overall, the most important thing is cherishing and spending time with people you love because nothing lasts forever.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[🎄]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">why documentation is important</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/documentation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="why documentation is important"/><published>2024-12-29T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-29T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/documentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/documentation/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <p>More recently, I’ve begun to think about the transfer of knowledge and information. Especially when working with multiple people/teams where tasks will inevitably be repeated by someone else or if that knowledge will be useful in the future, it’s important to store that information somewhere so it can be accessible later on.</p> <p>To me, documentation was always an annoying task to complete. <em>What if something changes and that documentation becomes obsolete and never used at all? What’s the point of spending time to write it then?</em></p> <p>Well, the opposite scenario can occur where there is little to no change and the documentation becomes extremely useful to people in the future. I’m someone who likes writing extremely detailed documentation so it’s definitely a laborious process, but here are some reasons why thorough documentation is important:</p> <p><br/></p> <h5 id="1-preserving-knowledge">1. Preserving Knowledge</h5> <p>When team members leave or move to different roles, documentation ensures that their knowledge isn’t lost and can be passed on to others. It provides a timeline of decisions, changes, and progress, making it easier to track the evolution of a project or system.</p> <h5 id="2-increases-efficiency">2. Increases Efficiency</h5> <p>By having documentation to look back on, others can replicate processes without having to waste time figuring things out on their own.</p> <h5 id="3-collaboration">3. Collaboration</h5> <p>Everyone involved has the same understanding and expectations. Standardization and guidelines also allow for consistency amongst everyone.</p> <h5 id="4-improves-quality">4. Improves Quality</h5> <p>Documentation can include sections for suggestions or logs of issues, which are valuable for iterative improvement. Good documentation also helps users utilize a product or system effectively.</p> <h5 id="5-supports-scalability">5. Supports Scalability</h5> <p>When systems or teams grow, documentation acts as a guide to ensure that expansion aligns with existing principles and practices. It provides a foundation for adapting processes or systems to new challenges or environments.</p> <p><br/></p> <p>In summary, documentation is a worthy investment in all scenarios. Whether you’re a teaching assistant documenting a process or at work documenting the functionality of your project, there’s no doubt that documentation you write will potentially save hours of labor and suffering. <strong>WRITE GOOD DOCUMENTATION!!</strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[📝]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">guide to PNW hikes</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-PNW-hikes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="guide to PNW hikes"/><published>2024-08-12T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-PNW-hikes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-PNW-hikes/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <h2 id="granola-girl-backstory">granola girl backstory</h2> <p>I’ve never been on a hike until I was 20 years old. During my first summer in Seattle, I went on a few hikes because my friends wanted to and I followed along because I didn’t want to be a party pooper. I discovered that there are a bunch of perks with hiking since I’m able to exercise my endurance and body while not having to do my least favorite sport – run. Additionally, I enjoy working hard for an outcome which is esentially what hiking entails. Hikers have to battle through the hike in order to (typically) reach the goal: the view.</p> <p>During my second summer in Seattle, my objective was to go on a hike every weekend since Washington’s nature is beautiful and more accessible than the hikes in California. I also needed some sort of consistent exercise with all of the free food I was getting 💀. Admittedly, I’ve become a granola girl and have bought a pair of hiking boots, a hiking backpack, trail mix, forest day passes, and rented some cars to just go hiking during Summer 2024. My next purchase will probably be a pair of hiking poles or a REI subscription 💀.</p> <p>I’m by no means an experienced hiker which is why I think it’d be nice to have reviews from someone who started hiking with no experience and also isn’t an incredibly fit athlete (introduces bias) either LOL. Additionally, I didn’t have a car during both summers so I wanted to share hikes I was able to go on without a car. Lastly, I’ve been asked by many people which hikes I’d recommend going on for beginners in Seattle so this is my comprehensive list.</p> <p>In this article, I’ll be listing the trail I went on, the length of the trail, difficulty, key details, and a summary of my hike. During Summer 2023, I lived in Capitol Hill and the UW area whereas in Summer 2024, I lived in Capitol Hill so transportation will be based off of those areas.</p> <p><br/></p> <h1 id="all-hikes-ive-been-on">All Hikes I’ve Been On</h1> <p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code> = accessible using <a href="https://trailheaddirect.org/">Trailhead Direct</a></p> <h2 id="summer-2023">Summer 2023</h2> <h3 id="mount-teneriffe-falls-">Mount Teneriffe Falls <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/teneriffe-falls-loop-via-the-mount-teneriffe-trail">Teneriffe Falls Loop via the Mount Teneiffe Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 5.9 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Hard</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Extremely rocky nearing the top, would recommend hiking poles and hiking boots</li> <li>The peak/view is just the waterfall, kind of lame considering how hard the hike was</li> <li>Bathrooms are gross but that’s to be expected</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>In hindsight, honestly cannot believe this was my first hike in Washington — kind of impressive considering the turn of events and how I almost died on this hike (read more here once I write this post lol)</li> <li>My friends and I brought alcoholic beverages (White Claws) and a coconut to share at the top</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> <h3 id="discovery-park">Discovery Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/south-beach-and-hidden-valley-loop-trail">South Beach and Hidden Valley Loop Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 2.4 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>HUGE park, basically a state park with a lot of easy trails</li> <li>The park attractions aren’t drivable (requires at least a little bit of walking)</li> <li>Transit is less accessible during the evening</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Got kind of lost on the trail especially with it getting dark</li> <li>Still had enough cell service to FaceTime someone and Lime scooter back to a bus stop</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su23.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su23.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su23.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su23.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Sunset @ Discovery Park </div> <h3 id="lake-22">Lake 22</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/lake-22-trail">Lake 22 Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Moderate</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Drove a rental car to this hike: commute is ~1.2 hour drive from the University of Washington to the trailhead parking</li> <li>Still snow near the lake in early July</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Friends swam in the lake, water was cold but didn’t look too dirty</li> <li>Enjoyable hike</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/lake22.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/lake22.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/lake22.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/lake22.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Lake 22 featuring snow </div> <h3 id="mount-rainier">Mount Rainier</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/skyline-trail">Skyline Loop</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Hard (personally thought it was moderate-hard)</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Drove a rental car to this hike: commute is ~1.5 hour drive from the University of Washington to the national park entrance</li> <li>Extremely popular national park and trail (in 2024, new reservation system implemented)</li> <li>First half is relatively unshaded with a lot of elevation</li> <li>Bathrooms are okay but there’s a long wait</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Beautiful but not sure if it’s worth the expenses, wait time, and parking struggles</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-1.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-1.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-1.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-1.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-2.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-2.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-2.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-2.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-3.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-3.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-3.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-3.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> <h3 id="poo-poo-point-">Poo Poo Point <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/poo-poo-point-trail">Poo Poo Point Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6.6 mi (only did half)</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Moderate (personally thought it was moderate-hard)</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Drove a rental car to this hike: commute is a ~30 minute drive from the University of Washington to the parking area but this was because I didn’t research on transportation options</li> <li>Beginning of the hike was extremely terrible with elevation, still scarred to this day</li> <li>Views of people paragliding but other than that… kind of lame</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Impulsively paraglided the hike down because the people offered my friend and I a discount LOL</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/poopoopoint.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/poopoopoint.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/poopoopoint.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/poopoopoint.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View from the top of Poo Poo Point </div> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="summer-2024">Summer 2024</h2> <h3 id="carkeek-park">Carkeek Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> Piper’s Creek Trail</li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 3.6 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Only a couple of trails</li> <li>One of the more accessible parks than the ones listed here</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Chill trail, I’m not a runner but I can tell it would be good to run through</li> <li>Salmon creek viewing area but I wasn’t able to see any in June</li> <li>Rocky beach at the coast</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/carkeek.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/carkeek.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/carkeek.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/carkeek.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View @ Carkeek Park </div> <h3 id="discovery-park-1">Discovery Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> Discovery Park and Lighthouse Loop</li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 4.5 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>HUGE park, basically a state park with a lot of easy trails</li> <li>The park attractions aren’t drivable (requires at least a little bit of walking)</li> <li>Transit is less accessible during the evening</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Lighthouse is kind of cool</li> <li>Sunset is beautiful</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24-2.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24-2.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24-2.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24-2.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> <h3 id="washington-park-arboretum">Washington Park Arboretum</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/the-washington-park-arboretum">Washington Park Arboretum</a> + <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/foster-island-trail">Foster Island Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 3.06 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Free and large</li> <li>Lots of beautiful nature, trees, and flowers to look at</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>I went on portions of these two trails because I wanted to see certain areas of the arboretum while also seeing the water.</li> <li>Foster Island Trail was very muddy and wet near the water - my shoes were absolutely ruined.</li> <li>Hiked with a boba during the later half</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/arboretum.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/arboretum.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/arboretum.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/arboretum.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Washington Park Arboretum </div> <h3 id="saint-edward-state-park">Saint Edward State Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/north-beach-south-canyon-orchard-juanita-arrowhead-loop">North, Beach, South Canyon, Orchard, Juanita, Arrowhead Loop</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 5.4 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Not public transit friendly - there are two busses that drop you off near the trailhead but they come very infrequently (once every hour)</li> <li>Beach is pretty lame and not accessible (can basically only enter to one section and you can’t spread out across the shore)</li> <li>Next to Bastyr University</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Had to hike an extra mile to get to the trailhead</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/st-edward.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/st-edward.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/st-edward.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/st-edward.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Bridge near shore @ Saint Edward State Park </div> <h3 id="seward-park">Seward Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/seward-park-perimeter-loop">Seward Park Perimeter Loop</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 3.31 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Transit friendly</li> <li>Contains multiple play structure areas and water refill stations</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Beautiful view of Mount Rainier</li> <li>Would be good to go on a run through</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/seward.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/seward.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/seward.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/seward.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View of Mount Rainier @ Seward Park </div> <h3 id="bridle-trails-state-park">Bridle Trails State Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/raven-and-coyote-trail-loop">Raven and Coyote Trail Loop</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6.51 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Lots of horse poop on the trail</li> <li>No views but solid trails</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>I stepped in horse poop</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/bridle-trails.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/bridle-trails.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/bridle-trails.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/bridle-trails.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> My lunch (grilled cheese, oranges, water) </div> <h3 id="cougar-mountain-regional-wildlife-park-">Cougar Mountain Regional Wildlife Park <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/big-tree-ridge-trail">Big Tree Ridge Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6.35 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Moderate</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>A bit of elevation to the viewpoint (also drivable)</li> <li>Large picnic areas at the top with tables and benches</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>View isn’t great but also isn’t terrible</li> <li>I got hives during this hike and also peed in the woods for the first time</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/cougar.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/cougar.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/cougar.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/cougar.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View @ the top of Cougar Mountain </div> <h3 id="little-si-">Little Si <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/little-si-trail">Little Si Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 4.5 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Moderate</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>The extremely smaller and less intense version of Mount Si</li> <li>Popular hike</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Everyone and their mom was at this hike when I went (an entire college club was hoarding the peak when I got there)</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/little-si.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/little-si.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/little-si.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/little-si.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View @ the top of Little Si </div> <h3 id="squak-mountain-">Squak Mountain <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/debbies-view-via-may-valley-loop-and-west-peak-trail">Debbie’s View via May Valley Loop and West Peak Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6.51 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Moderate (persnally thought it was moderate-hard)</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Not too popular</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Hike was kind of hard and am not sure if the view is worth it</li> <li>Raspberry bushes along the trail</li> <li>Cute Samoyed dogs at the peak when I went</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/squak.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/squak.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/squak.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/squak.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View @ the top of Squak Mountain </div> <h3 id="mount-si-">Mount Si <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/mount-si-trail">Mount Si Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 8.13 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Hard</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Relatively popular trail (apparently most Washington residents go on this hike at least once) among adults</li> <li>Very rocky at the top, would recommend hiking poles and hiking boots</li> <li>So many bugs and mosquitos, would recommend bug spray because stopping meant bugs swarming you</li> <li>Bathrooms are gross but that’s to be expected</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>I got 12 bug bites after this hike while wearing long pants</li> <li>My hip hurt to the point where putting on pants and socks was extremely uncomfortable after this hike (but I also hiked Squak Mountain the day before)</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/mount-si.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/mount-si.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/mount-si.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/mount-si.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View @ the top of Mount Si </div> <h3 id="colchuck-lake">Colchuck Lake</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/colchuck-lake-via-stuart-lake-trail">Colchuck Lake via Stuart Lake and Colchuck Lake Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 10.51 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Hard (personally thought moderate-hard)</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Drove a rental car to this hike: commute is ~3 hour drive from SeaTac to the trailhead parking</li> <li>Very uneven terrain to get to the parking area (would not bring my own car to this) and had to park 1 mile away from the trailhead</li> <li>Requires a parking pass ($5 per day)</li> <li>Extremely popular hike among all age groups</li> <li>Alpine lake at the peak of the hike, still snow in some areas in mid August</li> <li>Extremely rocky at the top, would recommend hiking poles and hiking boots</li> <li>So many bugs and mosquitos, would recommend bug spray because stopping meant bugs swarming you</li> <li>Bathrooms are gross but that’s to be expected</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>I had a lot of hype surrounding this hike and it was kind of disappointing. The hike overall was easier than Mount Si in terms of elevation but the length of the hike was more than its utility. Getting to the lake is difficult (scramble through rocky areas) and the water didn’t look too clean so I didn’t swim in it.</li> <li>I had a headache at the peak and all I wanted to do was go home but since the hike is so long, I had to hike 5 miles back and drive for another 3 hours.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/colchuck.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/colchuck.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/colchuck.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/colchuck.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Colchuck Lake </div> <p><br/></p> <h1 id="no-car-hikes">No Car Hikes</h1> <p>The parks in Washington are absolutely beautiful and larger than the suburban parks I’m used to which is why most have trails. I needed to also ease myself back into hiking which is why I went to a bunch of parks since they serve as good alternatives to more strenuous hiking trails.</p> <p>I didn’t have a car in Seattle but luckily, Washington has significantly better public transportation than California. Especially with all of the nature, there is the <a href="https://trailheaddirect.org/">Trailhead Direct</a> which operates during the weekends between late May till mid September. This is just an extension of the King County Metro where there are shuttles that drop riders off to some trailheads. Payment is through the ORCA card ($2.75 per ride) which I think is a great deal since the shuttles are relatively fast and you don’t have to drive after a tiring hike. The only downside is that the shuttles do get full fast so be sure to get there early and that the timings of the bus is inconsistent (but they do eventually come).</p> <p>During my second summer here, I had no friends but I still wanted to hike. It’s definitely a lot more riskier and cost-inefficient for solo hikers so I had to adapt and research hiking trails that were public transit-friendly. It was a bit difficult to find which trails were accessible so I wanted to compile a list for people who were in the same boat as me.</p> <ul> <li>Seward Park</li> <li>Carkeek Park</li> <li>Washington Park Arboretum</li> <li>Discovery Park</li> <li>Bridle Trails State Park</li> <li>Saint Edward State Park</li> <li>Cougar Mountain Regional Wildland Park</li> <li>Squak Mountain</li> <li>Mount Teneriffe Falls</li> <li>Little Si</li> <li>Mount Si</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h1 id="must-go-hikes">Must Go Hikes</h1> <p>While my time in Seattle has mostly come to an end 😞, these are the hikes I think are worth doing if you get the chance to be in the area!</p> <ul> <li>Lake 22</li> <li>Little Si</li> <li>Discovery Park</li> <li>Honorable Mention: Golden Gardens Park (the only beach with sand I’ve found in Washington)</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h1 id="index">Index</h1> <p>All Hikes:</p> <ul> <li>Mount Teneriffe Falls</li> <li>Discovery Park</li> <li>Lake 22</li> <li>Mount Rainier</li> <li>Poo Poo Point</li> <li>Carkeek Park</li> <li>Washington Park Arboretum</li> <li>Saint Edward State Park</li> <li>Seward Park</li> <li>Bridle Trails State Park</li> <li>Cougar Mountain Regional Wildlife Park</li> <li>Little Si</li> <li>Squak Mountain</li> <li>Mount Si</li> <li>Colchuck Lake</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="advice"/><category term="opinions"/><category term="travel"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[becoming a granola girl 🥾]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">guide to uc berkeley’s libraries</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-uc-berkeley-libraries/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="guide to uc berkeley’s libraries"/><published>2024-07-08T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-uc-berkeley-libraries</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-uc-berkeley-libraries/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li><strong>[May 16, 2025]</strong> done.</li> <li><strong>[December 26, 2024]</strong> 14/21 libraries visited.</li> <li><strong>[July 8, 2024]</strong> 12/21 libraries visited. my life is so boring lol</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="um-why">um… why?</h2> <p>One of my favorite aspects about UC Berkeley that I take for granted is the number of libraries on campus. It shocked me when I found out that most colleges have only a couple of libraries. If you met me in college, you probably associate rotting in libraries with me since I probably go to a library at least once a day. Surprisingly enough, I never really went to the library to get work done prior to college (which in hindight also makes sense since the libraries were a bit further away from my house and I had no mode of transportation).</p> <p>I enjoy working in libraries because I’m able to focus in a location where others are working as well. I call this “peer pressure”, where knowing the presence of others hard at work motivates me to be productive as well. Additionally, my apartment is further away from campus so it’s unideal for me to go back and forth from different locations when working, hence why I just go to a library.</p> <p>As such, my goal is to work in all of the accessible libraries at UC Berkeley by the time I graduate and to provide my opinion on all of them for anyone interested. The number of libraries vary but according to this <a href="https://www.lib.berkeley.edu/about/news/library-101">article</a>, there are 21 libraries (though not all are accessible for undergraduate students). I’ll be ranking them by the criteria below with a scale from 1 (worst) to 5 (best) with additional comments underneath (ex: needing to show Cal-ID). It’s difficult to rank which libraries I like best so I’ll notate my preferences on which ones to go to for certain needs.</p> <ul> <li>Ability to eat</li> <li>Ability to find an outlet</li> <li>Ability to find a seat</li> <li>Crowdedness</li> <li>Noise level</li> <li>Accessibility (duration of being open)</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="art-historyclassics-library">Art History/Classics Library</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code></li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>A few at one of the entrances</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Maybe 4 seats at one of the entrances</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5/5</code></li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code></li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1/5</code> <ul> <li>Extremely hidden library, I think I got lost twice trying to find it</li> </ul> </li> <li> <p><strong>Comments</strong></p> <ul> <li>This library is for graduate art students so undergrads aren’t able to book any rooms. In general though, it’s still a very small library</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> </li> </ul> <h4 id="bancroft-library">Bancroft Library</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>If you’re quiet enough and there aren’t as many ppl, yes</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Desks usually have one</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Generally spots available</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Tends to have tourists to view the architecture of this and Doe Library</li> <li>Busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Large and tall building so it’s kind of echoey but people are quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Opens early and closes around 9 PM throughout weekdays and weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Kind of confusing to first navigate since it’s connected to Doe Library, Main Stacks, and Moffitt</li> <li>Beautiful architecture</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="berkeley-law-library">Berkeley Law Library</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Drinks with a lid are allowed but no actual food</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>At basically every table</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Lots of tables</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Not too sure since I’ve only been here once but since you can only enter if you’re a Berkeley Law student, I assume it’s not crowded at all</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Graduate students are mature</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>With the restricted access, it’s not accessible to all students</li> <li>Also on the highest floor which is a bit of a trek from the front entrance</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Solid and serene library</li> <li>Reminds me of a modern Mainstacks with more natural lighting but sadly only law graduate students can enter</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="bioscience-natural-resources--public-health-vlsb">Bioscience, Natural Resources &amp; Public Health (VLSB)</h4> <p>🏆 <em>Best substitute for the more popular libraries during exam season</em></p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Wouldn’t recommend unless in a cubicle</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Hard to find unless at a cubicle or one of the main desks</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Large library, lots of seats</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Although large, it’s near one of the edges of campus so less traffic than the libraries at the center</li> <li>Can be busy during exam season</li> <li>One of the bigger libraries so there tends to be people throughout the day and visitors throughout VLSB because of cool science artifacts/posters scattered throughout the building (like a dinosaur skeleton outside the library entrance)</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code></li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Opens early and closes around 9-10 PM throughout weekdays and weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Somewhat difficult to navigate through initially</li> <li>Lots of levels</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="business-haas">Business (Haas)</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Easy to hide and eat</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Generally available at tables</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Large library, lots of seating</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Haas is at one of the edges/corners of campus that people don’t want to trek to so typically only Haas students use this library</li> <li>Can be busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Variable levels of loudness depending on the location</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Opens early and closes around 10 PM throughout weekdays and weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Have seen a couple of unharmful homeless people here throughout the day just sitting there</li> <li>The Haas buildings are more “modern” than the other areas on campus but the library looks kind of old</li> <li>Sometimes it’s a little warm/stuffy in there?</li> <li>Bookable rooms are pretty spacious but there was a really bad ant problem the last time I was there</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="chemistry-astronomy--physics">Chemistry, Astronomy &amp; Physics</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">True</code> <ul> <li>Doable depending on location</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Available at tables and desks, can even borrow power banks</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>2 floors, a good amount of seating throughout both</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Not as popular library</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Louder on the first floor</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes semi-early (8 PM) and open on weekends until 5 PM</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>The entrance is a bit difficult to find</li> <li>Honestly pleasantly pleased with this library since it has good lighting, good seating + outlets, and isn’t too quiet or crowded. The only con would probably be its location</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="doe">Doe</h4> <p>🏆 <em>Best architecture</em></p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Possible if in a more hidden location</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Personally hard to find if not at the large tables but even then, the outlets are connected to the lamp so larger powerblocks aren’t able to be plugged in</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Generally easy to find a seat with so many tables</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>One of the central libraries so lots of traffic and lots of general visitors because of the architecture</li> <li>Busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Echoey but quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Opens early and closes around 9 PM throughout weekdays and weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Beautiful architecture</li> <li>Connected with Bancroft, Moffitt, and Main Stacks</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/doe-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/doe-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/doe-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/doe.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> "Harry Potter"-esque interior </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="earth-sciences--map">Earth Sciences &amp; Map</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Not recommended</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>I think there were some next to the desks</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1/5</code> <ul> <li>Only saw like 1-3 tables</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Nobody goes here</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5/5</code> <ul> <li>Almost no noise</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes at 5 PM and not open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Located in one of the buildings near North Gate and is kind of hard to find</li> <li>Very old library containing lots of maps</li> <li>Closes early, wouldn’t recommend coming here to work for a long time</li> <li>I think only the people who work at the library go there</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="east-asian">East Asian</h4> <p>🏆 <em>Best views</em></p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Only possible if in a cubicle</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Difficult to find unless at table</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Personally thought it is difficult to find since the library isn’t too large</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Lots of traffic after noon</li> <li>Very busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Very quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes at 5 PM and not open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Probably the most beautiful library on campus with great views and natural sunlight</li> <li>Bookable rooms are available but can be difficult to find</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/east-asian-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/east-asian-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/east-asian-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/east-asian.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Views from top floor </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="engineering-kresge">Engineering (Kresge)</h4> <p>🏆 <em>Best for guaranteed seating to do short-term work</em></p> <p>NOTE: Review based on before renovation</p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Easy to do so</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Extremely easy to find throughout the library but kind of hard of cubicles ironically</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Lots of seating throughout the library, especially couch areas</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Very crowded since all of the engineering kids come here</li> <li>Very busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Talking is allowed so wouldn’t recommend coming here if you need to focus</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes late (I think midnight?) and open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Lots of bookable rooms - typically by CSM mentors</li> <li>Kind of musty</li> <li>Cool architecture, bunker style with an upper and lower floor</li> <li>Some unharmful homeless people</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/kresge-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/kresge-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/kresge-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/kresge.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Double-decker levels of Kresge </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="environmental-design-wurster">Environmental Design (Wurster)</h4> <p>🏆 Best for vibes</p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Wouldn’t recommend unless at the seating near the very edges of the library</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Generally available at the ends of the large tables</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Lots of tables so should be relatively easy to find</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Moderately filled throughout the day</li> <li>Surprisingly very busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>For a large library, very quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes late at 10 PM and open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>I love this library for some reason, I think it’s very spacious, clean, and quiet</li> <li>Only two bookable rooms - one is very large while the other is small</li> <li>Sometimes unharmful homeless people but not too often</li> <li>Two levels but I’ve never been/don’t know how to get to the second level (seems like a studio?)</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="ethnic-studies">Ethnic Studies</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code></li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Library is pretty small, didn’t seem like there were a lot of available outlets</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Very few tables and seats in the library since it’s so small</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>During dead week, it was surprisingly crowded</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code></li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes at 5pm and opens semi-late</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="institute-of-governmental-studies">Institute of Governmental Studies</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code></li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Library isn’t too large but there were outlets near every table</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>A few tables on the upper and lower levels</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Lesser known library so not too many people go to this library</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code></li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Even though it’s a lesser known library, it’s easy to find since it’s on the ground floor</li> <li>Closes at 5pm and opens semi-late</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="institute-of-transportation-studies">Institute of Transportation Studies</h4> <p>🏆 Cutest last-minute library find</p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code></li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Library isn’t too large but there were outlets near every table</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Most of the seating is at the center of the library. There’s also a small couch area</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Lesser known library so not too many people go to this library</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Can talk in this library</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Kind of hard to find</li> <li>Closes at 5pm and opens semi-late</li> <li>There are no women’s restrooms in the same building… you need to go to the adjacent connecting building to go to the library</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>There’s a ping pong table and basketball hoop in the library</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="main-gardner-stacks">Main (Gardner) Stacks</h4> <p>🏆 Best for grinding</p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Easy to do so if in a cubicle and really quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Almost guaranteed to have an outlet anywhere you decide to sit (excluding couches)</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Lots of seating whether it be at the large tables, cubicles, “peer pressure” desks, or couches</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Moderately filled throughout the day but traffic comes in and out</li> <li>Extremely packed during exam season, do not recommend</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5/5</code> <ul> <li>Dead silent</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes late (I think midnight or 2 AM) and open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Very hard to navigate when coming for the first time</li> <li>Underground library with five floors</li> <li>Meeting rooms are generally easy to book and not too popular but most come with chalk boards</li> <li>Wi-Fi can be spotty at different levels of the library and generally no data down there</li> <li>Recommend coming here for long study sessions, feels great to leave afterwards to feel the fresh air</li> <li>Can be cold or stuffy temperature-wise</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/mainstacks-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/mainstacks-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/mainstacks-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/mainstacks.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> "Peer pressure" desks in Main Stacks </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="mathematics-statistics">Mathematics Statistics</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Easy to do so if at the upper floor cubicles</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Cubicles on top floor don’t have outlets except for a few</li> <li>Public computer area has seating and outlets on the ground</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Cubicles, tables, couches, desks</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Traffic comes in and out throughout the day but generally should be able to find a seat</li> <li>One of the “lesser known” libraries on campus since it’s located on the first floor of Evans Hall</li> <li>More busy during exam season but still less compared to other libraries</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Surprisingly quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes at 8 PM and not open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Can be difficult to find initially</li> <li>Very old, musty and small library</li> <li>Good place to pop in and do some work for a short amount of time</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="moffitt">Moffitt</h4> <p>NOTE: Review based on before renovation</p> <p>🏆 <em>Best for eating</em></p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">True</code></li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Usually available at the desks and cubicles (if you’re able to get a seat…)</li> <li>Love the outlets at 4th floor couch areas</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Extremely difficult to find seating with desks at popular floors (4 and 5) but easier to find seating at Floors 1, 3 and 5</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1/5</code> <ul> <li>Most popular library on campus since it’s in the middle and eating is allowed</li> <li>Very busy during exam season, DO NOT recommend</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5/5</code> <ul> <li>Used to be 24 hour library but now closes at midnight and is open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1/5</code> <ul> <li>Depends on floor <ul> <li>1: Chatter (not too loud)</li> <li>3: Chatter (not too loud)</li> <li>4: Loud</li> <li>5: Generally quiet but occasional murmuring</li> </ul> </li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Lots of bookable rooms on Floors 4 and 5 with whiteboards</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/moffitt-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/moffitt-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/moffitt-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/moffitt.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Views of the Glade from the fifth floor </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="morrison">Morrison</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code></li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Available at desks? But limited</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>2 floors but a few desks, mostly a lot of couches for reading</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Not as popular library because you’re only supposed to read there</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1/5</code></li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>In an obscure location, closes relatively early and the second floor seems harder to access</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Do not use technology inside this library, you will get side-eyed</li> <li>Historical appearance</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="music">Music</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Doable depending on location (yes for cubicles)</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Available at desks and cubicles</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>3 floors but varying amounts of seating per floor (less on the top and basement floors)</li> <li>I love the cubicle area on the middle floor, lots of desks with outlets and is very private + quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Not as popular library</li> <li>More busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Quiet throughout</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes semi-early (8 PM) and open on weekends until 5 PM</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Beautiful library on the outside, kind of looks like Soda Hall (especially top floor)</li> <li>Ground to ceiling windows near some desks with views of Hearst Annex Field and walkways which can be distracting</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="social-research">Social Research</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Drinks with a lid are allowed</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Seemed like there were a couple at the tables</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Medium sized library, a good number of tables and seats</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>During dead week, it was pretty crowded but I think any other time, it shouldn’t be crowded since it’s in one of the Northwest buildings and kind of hard to find</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Some whispering allowed</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>This was one of the hardest libraries for me to find</li> <li>Building is old and the library is on the highest floor</li> </ul> </li> <li> <p><strong>Comments</strong></p> <ul> <li>Lots of natural lighting and the library seems very cozy/historic</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> </li> </ul> <h4 id="southsoutheast-asia">South/Southeast Asia</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Drinks with a lid are allowed</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Few at the tables and small cubicles</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Given the size of the library, the seating wasn’t bad since there are a few large tables, some couches and cubicles</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Library is tucked away so I doubt people are coming to it regularly</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code></li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Even though it’s not a popular library, the entrance is probably closer than going to Mainstacks and not too difficult to find</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Last library I went to on my bucket list and before graduating</li> <li>I thought this library was so cute, twas unfortunate that I discovered it during my last day of school LOL</li> </ul> </li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="advice"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[reviews and rankings of uc berkeley's numerous libraries from a frequent lib-goer]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">thoughts on bronny james</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/thoughts-on-bronny-james/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="thoughts on bronny james"/><published>2024-07-06T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-06T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/thoughts-on-bronny-james</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/thoughts-on-bronny-james/"><![CDATA[<p>bruh why am i writing about lebron james’ son, not even about the Warriors or Stephen Curry 😭</p> <hr/> <p>I’m conflicted on Bronny James. As a Warriors fan, I’m obligated to dislike his father, Lebron James. I definitely am not a fan of him but I respect his impact on the game of basketball and his dedication to positively impact whatever team he’s on. The main reason why I dislike Lebron is because of his cockiness and ego — like yes, he’s a good basketball player but I think it’s very egotistical of him to deem himself “The King” when there are loads of great basketball players throughout history.</p> <p>To be fair, I haven’t watched Bronny play too much except for the occasional highlight post/reel that pops up on my Instagram feed. However, I’ve never been impressed by any of his highlights (I think one of his highlights during his first NBA summer league game was an easy steal and pass 💀).</p> <p>He was selected 55th overall in the second round of the NBA 2024 draft. Did he deserve to be drafted? No, and here are my reasons and thoughts circulating him.</p> <blockquote> <p><strong>What are the odds that he gets drafted AND to the Lakers, the same team his father is on?</strong></p> </blockquote> <p>Bronny is barely 6’2”. That’s considered extremely short in the NBA. In Stephen Curry’s scouting report, coaches said that he’d be unlikely to find success in the league because of his height, mind you Curry is 6’3”. The fact that the Lakers ended up drafting him is extremely suspicious to me… the nepotism at hand is <strong>CRAZY</strong>.</p> <blockquote> <p><strong>Bronny was not the star player at USC.</strong></p> </blockquote> <p>During the 25 games he played during his freshman season (typically 35-40 games per season), he only averaged 4.8 points per game. He also only started in six of those games. Usually, a player can make up for less PPG by contributing to other stats like rebounds or assists but he only averaged 2.8 rebounds and 2.1 assists. <em>Numbers don’t lie…</em></p> <blockquote> <p><strong>He had a cardiac arrest, he deserves some slack.</strong></p> </blockquote> <p>Yes, it’s unfortunate that incident happened to him. However, it’s a bit suspicious to me because Bronny is young, incredibly fit, and healthy with access to the best trainers and doctors available. The timing of his cardiac arrest was also strange since it was right before the start of the college season and there were no instances of heart failure in the past. I’m aware that heart problems do randomly occur for some people but these are just some factors I’m wary about. <em>Was this a planned accident to get the media less focused on his success in the upcoming season and draft? Who knows…</em></p> <blockquote> <p><strong>How did he go from being hesitant on staying at USC/playing in college basketball to enrolling in the NBA draft?</strong></p> </blockquote> <p>For any other NBA prospect, there is absolutely <strong>NO WAY</strong> they would get drafted with Bronny’s stats and caliber. He was considering transferring colleges but then somehow made it to the draft? Additionally, rookies are rarely paid millions when drafted but he signed a $7.9 million contract across 4 years. <strong>HE HAS NEVER EVEN PLAYED FOR THEM</strong>, he has proved none of his skills to the team yet. He definitely improved leading up to the draft combine but still not up to par to other players. Yes, his jersey and position on the team will bring in lots of revenue which the NBA ultimately is, a business, but please…</p> <p>All in all, I think it’s incredibly unfair that Bronny was drafted when there were so many other players who have equally worked as hard (arguably more to be honest) to get to that position as he did. At the same time, I feel bad for Bronny because he has an immense amount of pressure on him, being the firstborn son of “The King”. I kind of feel bad for him because he’s getting more scrutinized than others but at the same time, he was cocky enough to only accept workouts from 3 teams… I wish him the best in his career, with such a low bar he’s setting, he’s sure to beat the odds.</p> <p>Ironically enough, he already got injured after one game. I feel like most of this is Lebron’s doing since he’s a stats-chaser and wants them to be the first active father-son duo in the NBA but I don’t know — <em>doesn’t it feel unsettling knowing that what you achieved wasn’t rightfully deserved?</em> But then again, money can buy happiness, or in this case, a career lol.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[my perspective on lebron james jr]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">reflecting</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/reflecting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="reflecting"/><published>2024-06-15T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-15T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/reflecting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/reflecting/"><![CDATA[<p><b></b></p> <p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">redacted</code> but sometimes it’s nice to just stop, rest, and think about life.</p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="opinions"/><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[basketball is really cool]]></summary></entry></feed>