<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-05-17T23:39:41+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">things i wish i knew before visiting japan</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/things-i-wish-i-knew-before-visiting-japan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="things i wish i knew before visiting japan"/><published>2024-05-14T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/things-i-wish-i-knew-before-visiting-japan</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/things-i-wish-i-knew-before-visiting-japan/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m currently in Japan while I’m drafting this post, unable to sleep because I randomly woke up at 2:30 AM and decided to work on this. This was my first time visiting Japan and the first international trip I’ve taken as a <em>competent</em> human being (aka not a kid). These are the things I wish I knew to make the travel process more seamless and the trip more fun — please don’t suffer like I did.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="essentials">Essentials</h2> <p>sorry this is a work in progress that i hope to wrap up on my flight, i have to add SO MANY more things</p> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="prior-to-trip">Prior to Trip</h3> <ul> <li>idk call the bank and ask them to not block your cards because otherwise, they think there’s a fraud and then you won’t be able to use your cards <blockquote> <p>Suica card is used for all the transit systems in Japan. Usually it’s a physical card but there’s an IC chip shortage so they aren’t giving them out to visitors as much. There’s a welcome Suica card but also not easily available anymore because of chip shortage.</p> </blockquote> </li> <li>Add Suica (or PASMOS) to your Apple Wallet <ul> <li>Transit</li> <li>You add money thru Apple wallet</li> <li>HAVE A MASTERCARD ON YOUR APPLE WALLET <ul> <li>only some Visa cards are accepted but Mastercard is guaranteed (call bank ahead to not block it)</li> </ul> </li> <li>The Suica card can be used for purchases too at some stores (mainly the convenience stores in my experience)</li> <li>So much easier to tap in and out of transit systems instead of having to buy paper tickets every time</li> </ul> </li> <li>lmfao plan your trip in advance <ol> <li>what cities do you want to visit</li> <li>proceed to book hotels there</li> <li>search at what activities to do, what places to eat</li> </ol> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="getting-from-narita-airport-to-tokyo">Getting from Narita Airport to Tokyo</h3> <ul> <li>took the train but was boomer so my parents and I sat at the reserved seat section, got checked by the train ppl so we had to move to another section, but it was also reserved seats?</li> <li>basically each train is split into reserved (more expensive) vs non reserved seating <ul> <li>non reserved seating is at the back of the train, usually cars 1-5</li> <li>it’ll say on the train car and on signs which car is reserved seating or not</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="getting-from-tokyo-to-osaka">Getting from Tokyo to Osaka</h3> <ul> <li>took bullet train</li> <li>Have to wait in line to get physical tickets</li> <li>Don’t accept Suica for some reason (unless I’m incompetent), used Visa card instead</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="my-itinerary">My Itinerary</h3> <p>narita –&gt; tokyo (1 day) –&gt; osaka (1 day) –&gt; kyoto (2 days) –&gt; nara (1 day) –&gt; shinjuku/tokyo (1 day) –&gt; narita</p> <h3 id="tldr">tldr</h3> <p>don’t travel with your parents.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="travel"/><category term="advice"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[essentials you should know as a first time visitor to japan]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">why blog?</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/why-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="why blog?"/><published>2024-05-12T12:24:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-12T12:24:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/why-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/why-blog/"><![CDATA[<p><b></b></p> <p>👋 Hello stranger reading this! I’m not sure why you’re here but this post explains why I want to blog.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="so-why">so why?</h2> <p><b></b></p> <p>A lot of people have told me that I’m a really quiet person and that they want to get to know be better. I’ve also been informed that people want to know what’s going on in my head. Truth be told, I’m usually “no thoughts, head empty”. I tend to not overthink things and mainly live (mostly) in the present because life is so unpredictable, something might happen to flip my world upside down so why bother planning every detail?</p> <p>When attempting to make my personal website years ago, I looked at a bunch of other websites for <em>inspiration</em> and I liked the aspect of having a blog/forum of my own opinions and thoughts. I found that section of those sites extremely appealing to read through since it was a way to get to know those people better. Specifically, UC Berkeley’s <a href="https://cs161.org">CS 161</a> course has a <a href="https://pedagogy.cs161.org/">pedagogy blog</a> that I found <strong>especially</strong> fascinating and thought-provoking. Thus, I wanted a persistent means of sharing my advice or opinions online.</p> <p>Personally, I don’t think anyone will read any of my posts because I’m boring but for a long time, I wanted to share a couple of my opinions and have a “diary” of some sort to see how my thinking has changed and/or transitioned over time. I love data and recording miniscule details so this is another means for that.</p> <p>Medium is another blog forum site which I’ve used before but there are article reading restrictions on that platform, in addition to me not wanting people to get notified when I post which is why I’m choosing to post on my own site.</p> <p>These opinions will be only affiliated with me and (probably) not edited or proof-read thoroughly, it’s just a method of me to thought dump and reflect as my life progresses. In actuality, it’s probably just me wasting my time by procrastinating. Hopefully I’ll be able to post semi-frequently during downtime but we’ll see… 🤡</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="random"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this post explains why I created a blog]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry></feed>