<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-01-12T04:15:07+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">my first semester as a TA</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/takeaways-from-ta/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="my first semester as a TA"/><published>2025-01-11T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-11T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/takeaways-from-ta</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/takeaways-from-ta/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>DISCLAIMER:</strong> These are the thoughts and opinions from one student after teaching two data science classes at UC Berkeley.</p> <hr/> <p>Being part of course staff has been one of my most valuable experiences as an undergraduate student. After the Fall 2024 semester, I wanted to share the lessons I’ve learned and things I’ve discovered as a first time teaching assistant (TA).</p> <p>Before that, I wanted to outline the process it took for me to become part of course staff. At Berkeley, there’s a lot of demand for being part of course staff and everyone’s journey to joining is different. The most general and straightforward approach is first being an academic intern (AI), tutor/reader, then teaching assistant. The course staff positions available also depend on the EE/CS/DS course since some courses might not have academic interns.</p> <p>These are the positions I held as part of course staff:</p> <ul> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring 2022</code>: Data 8 Academic Intern</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Summer 2022</code>: CS 61B(L) Academic Intern</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Fall 2022</code>: CS 61A Academic Intern</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Fall 2023</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Tutor</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring 2024</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Tutor</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Fall 2024</code>: Data 101 Teaching Assistant</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring 2025</code>: Data 101 Head Teaching Assistant</li> </ul> <p>These are the positions I held as part of <a href="https://csmentors.studentorg.berkeley.edu/#/">Computer Science Mentors (CSM)</a> @ Berkeley where I taught weekly tutoring sections for a group of 4-5 students:</p> <ul> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Fall 2022</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Junior Mentor</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring 2023</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Senior Mentor</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Fall 2023</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Senior Mentor</li> <li><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Spring 2024</code>: CS 88 / Data C88C Senior Mentor</li> </ul> <p>Prior to getting those positions, I was continuously rejected from course staff until I eventually gained more experience and refined my application. Even though I’ve spent almost every semester teaching, I still have <strong>SO MUCH</strong> to improve on. There have been multiple instances where I didn’t know the answer to a student’s question or stumbled when mini-lecturing, but that’s a reason why I continue to teach — so I can continue improving as an instructor and help others learn.</p> <p>When transitioning from being a tutor to a TA, I thought that there wouldn’t be too big of a change with the exception of running my own discussion section individually. However, there were a lot of differences that I didn’t anticipate. As a disclaimer, these are five takeaways from one student after teaching two data science classes at Berkeley.</p> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="1-exam-logistics-are-a-lot-of-work">1. Exam logistics are a lot of work</h2> <p>Teaching assistants usually have a focus area, such as proofreading discussion worksheets, labs, projects, etc. My focus area was admin/logistics, meaning that I was in charge of managing weekly announcements, course email inbox, all exam logistics (room/seating assignments for students, staff proctoring and grading logistics, exam review sessions) for midterm and final exams, feedback forms, and the basic TA duties of teaching + office hours.</p> <p>Prior to being a Logistics TA, I never knew how much work went into holding an exam. At Berkeley, typically the week or a few days before an exam, students will receive an email stating their assigned room location and optionally, their assigned seat. I never thought too much about that email but the process it takes to book exam rooms, accommodate exam preferences (ex: left-handed seats), assign seats, etc is extremely lengthy and time consuming. When running exams, regular and DSP (<a href="https://dsp.berkeley.edu/home">Disabled Students’ Program</a>) students need to be accounted for and there’s additional logistics to account for if there are alternate exams. And that’s just for holding the exam, not to mention exam review sessions, writing the exam (dependent on course), and grading the exam…</p> <p>I remember spending hours on exam logistics and quite literally manually assigning 200 students’ seats because we didn’t have enough seats from the exam rooms provided, causing the Seating Tool to not work effectively.</p> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="2-student-support-is-important">2. Student support is important</h2> <p>Throughout the semester, since I was monitoring the staff email inbox, I categorized which emails pertained to which TA. There were hundreds of emails requesting for additional student support because of personal issues and even more leading up to exams or deadlines. Before this, I never knew how many students contacted course staff and the answer is, hundreds.</p> <p>There’s a lot of variance between courses on the extent of support from course staff. Typically, there’s a lot less or none for upper division courses because students are expected to be able to handle the rigor. However, I personally believe that there should always be student support in any course because unexpected circumstances occur out of one’s control and it’s a lot to handle while balancing school. Depending on the circumstances, it’s sometimes okay for a course to be less accommodating but generally, I believe that it’s best practice to thoroughly evaluate the scenario before arriving at a conclusion.</p> <p>For courses that provide student support, it takes up a lot more time than you think. Typically, each student that requires support results in multiple student support meetings that range from 15 min to hour long meetings, then you have to multiply that for every single student that wants or needs additional support. This especially builds up around exams or deadlines which takes up a lot of time for the student support TA.</p> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="3-established-vs-developing-courses">3. Established vs. developing courses</h2> <p>The first course I taught was <a href="https://c88c.org/fa23/">CS 88 / Data C88C</a>, which is the lower division fundamentals data science course that is built on top of CS 61A, an even older course. The next course I taught was <a href="https://data101.org/fa24/">Data 101</a>, which is the upper division data engineering course. Data 101 has only been offered for five semesters as of Spring 2025, meaning that the course changes every semester (for improvements) in comparison to CS 88 rarely changing.</p> <p>With all of the changes, course staff needs to be able to adapt to additional content being added. I remember some instances where the students and I were learning at the same time, except I also needed to be able to teach it during my own discussion section.</p> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="4-teaching-lower-division-vs-upper-division-courses">4. Teaching lower division vs. upper division courses</h2> <p>Adding on to the differences between teaching CS 88 and Data 101, the largest takeaway is probably the type of students I taught. In lower division courses, students are a lot less knowledgeable so there are a lot more “basic” questions, especially since CS 88 is an introduction to programming. However, in upper division courses, students are more familiar with programming and ask more conceptual-based questions that I sometimes didn’t know the answer to. Additionally, I typically didn’t know the students I taught in CS 88 since lower classmen (freshman, sophomores) took that class whereas in Data 101, I taught students that I knew or shared classes with which was sometimes weird. For instance, it puts staff in a weird position if students ask for help through Instagram direct messages…</p> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="5-cs-education-is-intriguing">5. CS education is intriguing</h2> <p>Not much more to it. I never enjoyed or found research too interesting but especially after TAing, it’s an avenue I want to dive deeper into.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="opinions"/><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[some takeaways]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">christmas</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/christmas/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="christmas"/><published>2025-01-10T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-01-10T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/christmas</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2025/christmas/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <p>Everyone has different traditions and activities so here is how my family does Christmas, alongside my thoughts. I also want to preface this post with it being entirely a rant and my own opinions/perspectives since I know I’m extremely privileged and grateful to be able to even have the luxury to relax during the holidays.</p> <p>Looking back, I can only recall my family decorating and putting up a Christmas tree three times, all occurrences before entering middle school. There were probably a few more instances of the tree being put up when I was really little but I don’t really remember those times. My family isn’t Christian but Christmas is such a global holiday that most people celebrate it, especially given its presence in various media forms (ex: books, movies, shows, etc).</p> <p><em>So, why doesn’t my family celebrate Christmas?</em></p> <p>I think the main reason is because my parents never celebrated it growing up either. Since they immigrated to America during their teenage years, they didn’t get much exposure to those festivities while trying to make ends meet.</p> <p>Once they got older and learned more about the culture, they tried integrating aspects of it when raising my siblings and I by mainly putting up a Christmas tree. Since we infrequently put up the Christmas tree, I literally only remember decorating it three times and always getting excited to see the darkness being illuminated by the tree’s lights — it made me feel comfy and I just liked being near the tree. Personally, I think that this doesn’t reinforce the main takeaways of Christmas such as being able to spend time with family and learning how to be selfless.</p> <p>As a child, I remember only thinking about what presents I would get. I would only get one gift from my parents and they always prefaced it with “you can choose whatever you want as long as it’s not too expensive”. With that reasoning, I never believed in Santa Claus because my parents never did activities such as snowy footprints to pretend that Santa dropped off presents under our tree. My house also doesn’t have a chimney so… there’s that haha</p> <p>As a teenager, Christmas still revolved around presents. My family is disjoint from both sides of the family so we never had a lot of presents in the first place or family gatherings, usually just presents from my parents and our cousins that are close in age. However, my parents started a newer tradition of going to Lake Tahoe with our cousins during winter break since we had all never been before. This allowed us to have more family time and therefore marked the end of us putting up the Christmas tree since we had stopped for a couple of years. Going to Lake Tahoe is always special to me because it’s the only vacation that my family goes on since we don’t travel much. I remember always being excited the night before leaving and being in awe when seeing snow.</p> <p>With the pandemic occurring and college applications rolling around in 2019, my family stopped going to Tahoe. Winter break became a time for me to initially rest, then grind during high school and college.</p> <p>Especially with extended family arguments, Christmas is just an ordinary day during winter break for my family and I. There is no Christmas tree, Christmas presents, Tahoe trip, or family gatherings. Whenever I receive text messages from friends wishing me “Merry Christmas” or “Happy New Year”, it always makes me feel weird (in some sense) since my family doesn’t celebrate those holidays.</p> <p>As I’ve grown older, presents hold less value and seeing various traditions on social media sometimes made me a bit envious of how close people are to their family and friends. Children experiencing the magic of Christmas is an event that can only happen once in a lifetime before it gets ruined. Even playing silly holiday games or participating in White Elephant seems so fun. Perhaps my siblings and I can be the change once we’re older and establish new traditions.</p> <p>My dad denoted this Christmas as the “worst Christmas ever” because my grandma suffered from a stroke a few days prior, causing her to be hospitalized for three weeks as of this post. Spending Christmas and in general, a lot of time at the hospital was a very impactful experience for me and allowed me to truly reflect about the time we have alive. It made me feel so sad to see patients helpless, trying their best to get healthy. Additionally, hospital workers have to deal with so much emotional baggage with each patient they interact with. I’m not going to go more into specifics but overall, the most important thing is cherishing and spending time with people you love because nothing lasts forever.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[🎄]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">why documentation is important</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/documentation/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="why documentation is important"/><published>2024-12-29T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-12-29T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/documentation</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/documentation/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <p>More recently, I’ve begun to think about the transfer of knowledge and information. Especially when working with multiple people/teams where tasks will inevitably be repeated by someone else or if that knowledge will be useful in the future, it’s important to store that information somewhere so it can be accessible later on.</p> <p>To me, documentation was always an annoying task to complete. <em>What if something changes and that documentation becomes obsolete and never used at all? What’s the point of spending time to write it then?</em></p> <p>Well, the opposite scenario can occur where there is little to no change and the documentation becomes extremely useful to people in the future. I’m someone who likes writing extremely detailed documentation so it’s definitely a laborious process, but here are some reasons why thorough documentation is important:</p> <p><br/></p> <h5 id="1-preserving-knowledge">1. Preserving Knowledge</h5> <p>When team members leave or move to different roles, documentation ensures that their knowledge isn’t lost and can be passed on to others. It provides a timeline of decisions, changes, and progress, making it easier to track the evolution of a project or system.</p> <h5 id="2-increases-efficiency">2. Increases Efficiency</h5> <p>By having documentation to look back on, others can replicate processes without having to waste time figuring things out on their own.</p> <h5 id="3-collaboration">3. Collaboration</h5> <p>Everyone involved has the same understanding and expectations. Standardization and guidelines also allow for consistency amongst everyone.</p> <h5 id="4-improves-quality">4. Improves Quality</h5> <p>Documentation can include sections for suggestions or logs of issues, which are valuable for iterative improvement. Good documentation also helps users utilize a product or system effectively.</p> <h5 id="5-supports-scalability">5. Supports Scalability</h5> <p>When systems or teams grow, documentation acts as a guide to ensure that expansion aligns with existing principles and practices. It provides a foundation for adapting processes or systems to new challenges or environments.</p> <p><br/></p> <p>In summary, documentation is a worthy investment in all scenarios. Whether you’re a teaching assistant documenting a process or at work documenting the functionality of your project, there’s no doubt that documentation you write will potentially save hours of labor and suffering. <strong>WRITE GOOD DOCUMENTATION!!</strong></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[📝]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">guide to PNW hikes</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-PNW-hikes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="guide to PNW hikes"/><published>2024-08-12T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-08-12T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-PNW-hikes</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-PNW-hikes/"><![CDATA[<hr/> <h2 id="granola-girl-backstory">granola girl backstory</h2> <p>I’ve never been on a hike until I was 20 years old. During my first summer in Seattle, I went on a few hikes because my friends wanted to and I followed along because I didn’t want to be a party pooper. I discovered that there are a bunch of perks with hiking since I’m able to exercise my endurance and body while not having to do my least favorite sport – run. Additionally, I enjoy working hard for an outcome which is esentially what hiking entails. Hikers have to battle through the hike in order to (typically) reach the goal: the view.</p> <p>During my second summer in Seattle, my objective was to go on a hike every weekend since Washington’s nature is beautiful and more accessible than the hikes in California. I also needed some sort of consistent exercise with all of the free food I was getting 💀. Admittedly, I’ve become a granola girl and have bought a pair of hiking boots, a hiking backpack, trail mix, forest day passes, and rented some cars to just go hiking during Summer 2024. My next purchase will probably be a pair of hiking poles or a REI subscription 💀.</p> <p>I’m by no means an experienced hiker which is why I think it’d be nice to have reviews from someone who started hiking with no experience and also isn’t an incredibly fit athlete (introduces bias) either LOL. Additionally, I didn’t have a car during both summers so I wanted to share hikes I was able to go on without a car. Lastly, I’ve been asked by many people which hikes I’d recommend going on for beginners in Seattle so this is my comprehensive list.</p> <p>In this article, I’ll be listing the trail I went on, the length of the trail, difficulty, key details, and a summary of my hike. During Summer 2023, I lived in Capitol Hill and the UW area whereas in Summer 2024, I lived in Capitol Hill so transportation will be based off of those areas.</p> <p><br/></p> <h1 id="all-hikes-ive-been-on">All Hikes I’ve Been On</h1> <p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code> = accessible using <a href="https://trailheaddirect.org/">Trailhead Direct</a></p> <h2 id="summer-2023">Summer 2023</h2> <h3 id="mount-teneriffe-falls-">Mount Teneriffe Falls <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/teneriffe-falls-loop-via-the-mount-teneriffe-trail">Teneriffe Falls Loop via the Mount Teneiffe Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 5.9 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Hard</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Extremely rocky nearing the top, would recommend hiking poles and hiking boots</li> <li>The peak/view is just the waterfall, kind of lame considering how hard the hike was</li> <li>Bathrooms are gross but that’s to be expected</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>In hindsight, honestly cannot believe this was my first hike in Washington — kind of impressive considering the turn of events and how I almost died on this hike (read more here once I write this post lol)</li> <li>My friends and I brought alcoholic beverages (White Claws) and a coconut to share at the top</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-falls.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-alc.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/teneriffe-group.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> <h3 id="discovery-park">Discovery Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/south-beach-and-hidden-valley-loop-trail">South Beach and Hidden Valley Loop Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 2.4 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>HUGE park, basically a state park with a lot of easy trails</li> <li>The park attractions aren’t drivable (requires at least a little bit of walking)</li> <li>Transit is less accessible during the evening</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Got kind of lost on the trail especially with it getting dark</li> <li>Still had enough cell service to FaceTime someone and Lime scooter back to a bus stop</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su23.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su23.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su23.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su23.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Sunset @ Discovery Park </div> <h3 id="lake-22">Lake 22</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/lake-22-trail">Lake 22 Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Moderate</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Drove a rental car to this hike: commute is ~1.2 hour drive from the University of Washington to the trailhead parking</li> <li>Still snow near the lake in early July</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Friends swam in the lake, water was cold but didn’t look too dirty</li> <li>Enjoyable hike</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/lake22.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/lake22.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/lake22.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/lake22.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Lake 22 featuring snow </div> <h3 id="mount-rainier">Mount Rainier</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/skyline-trail">Skyline Loop</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Hard (personally thought it was moderate-hard)</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Drove a rental car to this hike: commute is ~1.5 hour drive from the University of Washington to the national park entrance</li> <li>Extremely popular national park and trail (in 2024, new reservation system implemented)</li> <li>First half is relatively unshaded with a lot of elevation</li> <li>Bathrooms are okay but there’s a long wait</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Beautiful but not sure if it’s worth the expenses, wait time, and parking struggles</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-1.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-1.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-1.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-1.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-2.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-2.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-2.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-2.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-3.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-3.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-3.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/rainier-3.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> <h3 id="poo-poo-point-">Poo Poo Point <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/poo-poo-point-trail">Poo Poo Point Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6.6 mi (only did half)</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Moderate (personally thought it was moderate-hard)</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Drove a rental car to this hike: commute is a ~30 minute drive from the University of Washington to the parking area but this was because I didn’t research on transportation options</li> <li>Beginning of the hike was extremely terrible with elevation, still scarred to this day</li> <li>Views of people paragliding but other than that… kind of lame</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Impulsively paraglided the hike down because the people offered my friend and I a discount LOL</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/poopoopoint.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/poopoopoint.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/poopoopoint.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/poopoopoint.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View from the top of Poo Poo Point </div> <p><br/></p> <h2 id="summer-2024">Summer 2024</h2> <h3 id="carkeek-park">Carkeek Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> Piper’s Creek Trail</li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 3.6 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Only a couple of trails</li> <li>One of the more accessible parks than the ones listed here</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Chill trail, I’m not a runner but I can tell it would be good to run through</li> <li>Salmon creek viewing area but I wasn’t able to see any in June</li> <li>Rocky beach at the coast</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/carkeek.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/carkeek.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/carkeek.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/carkeek.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View @ Carkeek Park </div> <h3 id="discovery-park-1">Discovery Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> Discovery Park and Lighthouse Loop</li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 4.5 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>HUGE park, basically a state park with a lot of easy trails</li> <li>The park attractions aren’t drivable (requires at least a little bit of walking)</li> <li>Transit is less accessible during the evening</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Lighthouse is kind of cool</li> <li>Sunset is beautiful</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <swiper-container keyboard="true" navigation="true" pagination="true" pagination-clickable="true" pagination-dynamic-bullets="true" rewind="true"> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> <swiper-slide> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24-2.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24-2.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24-2.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/discovery-su24-2.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </swiper-slide> </swiper-container> <h3 id="washington-park-arboretum">Washington Park Arboretum</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/the-washington-park-arboretum">Washington Park Arboretum</a> + <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/foster-island-trail">Foster Island Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 3.06 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Free and large</li> <li>Lots of beautiful nature, trees, and flowers to look at</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>I went on portions of these two trails because I wanted to see certain areas of the arboretum while also seeing the water.</li> <li>Foster Island Trail was very muddy and wet near the water - my shoes were absolutely ruined.</li> <li>Hiked with a boba during the later half</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/arboretum.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/arboretum.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/arboretum.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/arboretum.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Washington Park Arboretum </div> <h3 id="saint-edward-state-park">Saint Edward State Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/north-beach-south-canyon-orchard-juanita-arrowhead-loop">North, Beach, South Canyon, Orchard, Juanita, Arrowhead Loop</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 5.4 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Not public transit friendly - there are two busses that drop you off near the trailhead but they come very infrequently (once every hour)</li> <li>Beach is pretty lame and not accessible (can basically only enter to one section and you can’t spread out across the shore)</li> <li>Next to Bastyr University</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Had to hike an extra mile to get to the trailhead</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/st-edward.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/st-edward.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/st-edward.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/st-edward.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Bridge near shore @ Saint Edward State Park </div> <h3 id="seward-park">Seward Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/seward-park-perimeter-loop">Seward Park Perimeter Loop</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 3.31 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Transit friendly</li> <li>Contains multiple play structure areas and water refill stations</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Beautiful view of Mount Rainier</li> <li>Would be good to go on a run through</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/seward.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/seward.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/seward.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/seward.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View of Mount Rainier @ Seward Park </div> <h3 id="bridle-trails-state-park">Bridle Trails State Park</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/raven-and-coyote-trail-loop">Raven and Coyote Trail Loop</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6.51 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Easy</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Lots of horse poop on the trail</li> <li>No views but solid trails</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>I stepped in horse poop</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/bridle-trails.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/bridle-trails.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/bridle-trails.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/bridle-trails.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> My lunch (grilled cheese, oranges, water) </div> <h3 id="cougar-mountain-regional-wildlife-park-">Cougar Mountain Regional Wildlife Park <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/big-tree-ridge-trail">Big Tree Ridge Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6.35 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Moderate</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>A bit of elevation to the viewpoint (also drivable)</li> <li>Large picnic areas at the top with tables and benches</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>View isn’t great but also isn’t terrible</li> <li>I got hives during this hike and also peed in the woods for the first time</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/cougar.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/cougar.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/cougar.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/cougar.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View @ the top of Cougar Mountain </div> <h3 id="little-si-">Little Si <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/little-si-trail">Little Si Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 4.5 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Moderate</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>The extremely smaller and less intense version of Mount Si</li> <li>Popular hike</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Everyone and their mom was at this hike when I went (an entire college club was hoarding the peak when I got there)</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/little-si.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/little-si.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/little-si.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/little-si.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View @ the top of Little Si </div> <h3 id="squak-mountain-">Squak Mountain <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/debbies-view-via-may-valley-loop-and-west-peak-trail">Debbie’s View via May Valley Loop and West Peak Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 6.51 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Moderate (persnally thought it was moderate-hard)</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Not too popular</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>Hike was kind of hard and am not sure if the view is worth it</li> <li>Raspberry bushes along the trail</li> <li>Cute Samoyed dogs at the peak when I went</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/squak.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/squak.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/squak.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/squak.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View @ the top of Squak Mountain </div> <h3 id="mount-si-">Mount Si <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code></h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/mount-si-trail">Mount Si Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 8.13 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Hard</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Relatively popular trail (apparently most Washington residents go on this hike at least once) among adults</li> <li>Very rocky at the top, would recommend hiking poles and hiking boots</li> <li>So many bugs and mosquitos, would recommend bug spray because stopping meant bugs swarming you</li> <li>Bathrooms are gross but that’s to be expected</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>I got 12 bug bites after this hike while wearing long pants</li> <li>My hip hurt to the point where putting on pants and socks was extremely uncomfortable after this hike (but I also hiked Squak Mountain the day before)</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/mount-si.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/mount-si.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/mount-si.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/mount-si.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> View @ the top of Mount Si </div> <h3 id="colchuck-lake">Colchuck Lake</h3> <ul> <li><strong>Trail:</strong> <a href="https://www.alltrails.com/ar/trail/us/washington/colchuck-lake-via-stuart-lake-trail">Colchuck Lake via Stuart Lake and Colchuck Lake Trail</a></li> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 10.51 mi</li> <li><strong>Difficulty:</strong> Hard (personally thought moderate-hard)</li> <li><strong>Key Details:</strong> <ul> <li>Drove a rental car to this hike: commute is ~3 hour drive from SeaTac to the trailhead parking</li> <li>Very uneven terrain to get to the parking area (would not bring my own car to this) and had to park 1 mile away from the trailhead</li> <li>Requires a parking pass ($5 per day)</li> <li>Extremely popular hike among all age groups</li> <li>Alpine lake at the peak of the hike, still snow in some areas in mid August</li> <li>Extremely rocky at the top, would recommend hiking poles and hiking boots</li> <li>So many bugs and mosquitos, would recommend bug spray because stopping meant bugs swarming you</li> <li>Bathrooms are gross but that’s to be expected</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Summary:</strong> <ul> <li>I had a lot of hype surrounding this hike and it was kind of disappointing. The hike overall was easier than Mount Si in terms of elevation but the length of the hike was more than its utility. Getting to the lake is difficult (scramble through rocky areas) and the water didn’t look too clean so I didn’t swim in it.</li> <li>I had a headache at the peak and all I wanted to do was go home but since the hike is so long, I had to hike 5 miles back and drive for another 3 hours.</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/colchuck.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/colchuck.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/hiking/colchuck.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/hiking/colchuck.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Colchuck Lake </div> <p><br/></p> <h1 id="no-car-hikes">No Car Hikes</h1> <p>The parks in Washington are absolutely beautiful and larger than the suburban parks I’m used to which is why most have trails. I needed to also ease myself back into hiking which is why I went to a bunch of parks since they serve as good alternatives to more strenuous hiking trails.</p> <p>I didn’t have a car in Seattle but luckily, Washington has significantly better public transportation than California. Especially with all of the nature, there is the <a href="https://trailheaddirect.org/">Trailhead Direct</a> which operates during the weekends between late May till mid September. This is just an extension of the King County Metro where there are shuttles that drop riders off to some trailheads. Payment is through the ORCA card ($2.75 per ride) which I think is a great deal since the shuttles are relatively fast and you don’t have to drive after a tiring hike. The only downside is that the shuttles do get full fast so be sure to get there early and that the timings of the bus is inconsistent (but they do eventually come).</p> <p>During my second summer here, I had no friends but I still wanted to hike. It’s definitely a lot more riskier and cost-inefficient for solo hikers so I had to adapt and research hiking trails that were public transit-friendly. It was a bit difficult to find which trails were accessible so I wanted to compile a list for people who were in the same boat as me.</p> <ul> <li>Seward Park</li> <li>Carkeek Park</li> <li>Washington Park Arboretum</li> <li>Discovery Park</li> <li>Bridle Trails State Park</li> <li>Saint Edward State Park</li> <li>Cougar Mountain Regional Wildland Park</li> <li>Squak Mountain</li> <li>Mount Teneriffe Falls</li> <li>Little Si</li> <li>Mount Si</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h1 id="must-go-hikes">Must Go Hikes</h1> <p>While my time in Seattle has mostly come to an end 😞, these are the hikes I think are worth doing if you get the chance to be in the area!</p> <ul> <li>Lake 22</li> <li>Little Si</li> <li>Discovery Park</li> <li>Honorable Mention: Golden Gardens Park (the only beach with sand I’ve found in Washington)</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h1 id="index">Index</h1> <p>All Hikes:</p> <ul> <li>Mount Teneriffe Falls</li> <li>Discovery Park</li> <li>Lake 22</li> <li>Mount Rainier</li> <li>Poo Poo Point</li> <li>Carkeek Park</li> <li>Washington Park Arboretum</li> <li>Saint Edward State Park</li> <li>Seward Park</li> <li>Bridle Trails State Park</li> <li>Cougar Mountain Regional Wildlife Park</li> <li>Little Si</li> <li>Squak Mountain</li> <li>Mount Si</li> <li>Colchuck Lake</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="advice"/><category term="opinions"/><category term="travel"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[becoming a granola girl 🥾]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">guide to uc berkeley’s libraries</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-uc-berkeley-libraries/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="guide to uc berkeley’s libraries"/><published>2024-07-08T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-08T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-uc-berkeley-libraries</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/guide-to-uc-berkeley-libraries/"><![CDATA[<ul> <li><strong>[December 26, 2024]</strong> 14/18 libraries visited.</li> <li><strong>[July 8, 2024]</strong> 12/18 libraries visited. my life is so boring lol</li> </ul> <hr/> <h2 id="um-why">um… why?</h2> <p>One of my favorite aspects about UC Berkeley that I take for granted is the number of libraries on campus. It shocked me when I found out that most colleges have only a couple of libraries. If you met me in college, you probably associate rotting in libraries with me since I probably go to a library at least once a day. Surprisingly enough, I never really went to the library to get work done prior to college (which in hindight also makes sense since the libraries were a bit further away from my house and I had no mode of transportation).</p> <p>I enjoy working in libraries because I’m able to focus in a location where others are working as well. I call this “peer pressure”, where knowing the presence of others hard at work motivates me to be productive as well. Additionally, my apartment is further away from campus so it’s unideal for me to go back and forth from different locations when working, hence why I just go to a library.</p> <p>As such, my goal is to work in all of the accessible libraries at UC Berkeley by the time I graduate and to provide my opinion on all of them for anyone interested. The number of libraries vary but according to this <a href="https://www.lib.berkeley.edu/about/news/library-101">article</a>, there are 20 libraries (though not all are accessible for undergraduate students). I’ll be ranking them by the criteria below with a scale from 1 (worst) to 5 (best) with additional comments underneath (ex: needing to show Cal-ID). It’s difficult to rank which libraries I like best so I’ll notate my preferences on which ones to go to for certain needs.</p> <ul> <li>Ability to eat</li> <li>Ability to find an outlet</li> <li>Ability to find a seat</li> <li>Crowdedness</li> <li>Noise level</li> <li>Accessibility (duration of being open)</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="bancroft-library">Bancroft Library</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>If you’re quiet enough and there aren’t as many ppl, yes</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Desks usually have one</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Generally spots available</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Tends to have tourists to view the architecture of this and Doe Library</li> <li>Busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Large and tall building so it’s kind of echoey but people are quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Opens early and closes around 9 PM throughout weekdays and weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Kind of confusing to first navigate since it’s connected to Doe Library, Main Stacks, and Moffitt</li> <li>Beautiful architecture</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="berkeley-law-library">Berkeley Law Library</h4> <ul> <li>TBA</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="bioscience-natural-resources--public-health-vlsb">Bioscience, Natural Resources &amp; Public Health (VLSB)</h4> <p>🏆 <em>Best substitute for the more popular libraries during exam season</em></p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Wouldn’t recommend unless in a cubicle</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Hard to find unless at a cubicle or one of the main desks</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Large library, lots of seats</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Although large, it’s near one of the edges of campus so less traffic than the libraries at the center</li> <li>Can be busy during exam season</li> <li>One of the bigger libraries so there tends to be people throughout the day and visitors throughout VLSB because of cool science artifacts/posters scattered throughout the building (like a dinosaur skeleton outside the library entrance)</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code></li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Opens early and closes around 9-10 PM throughout weekdays and weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Somewhat difficult to navigate through initially</li> <li>Lots of levels</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="business-haas">Business (Haas)</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Easy to hide and eat</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Generally available at tables</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Large library, lots of seating</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Haas is at one of the edges/corners of campus that people don’t want to trek to so typically only Haas students use this library</li> <li>Can be busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Variable levels of loudness depending on the location</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Opens early and closes around 10 PM throughout weekdays and weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Have seen a couple of unharmful homeless people here throughout the day just sitting there</li> <li>The Haas buildings are more “modern” than the other areas on campus but the library looks kind of old</li> <li>Sometimes it’s a little warm/stuffy in there?</li> <li>Bookable rooms are pretty spacious but there was a really bad ant problem the last time I was there</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="chemistry-astronomy--physics">Chemistry, Astronomy &amp; Physics</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">True</code> <ul> <li>Doable depending on location</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Available at tables and desks, can even borrow power banks</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>2 floors, a good amount of seating throughout both</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Not as popular library</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Louder on the first floor</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes semi-early (8 PM) and open on weekends until 5 PM</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>The entrance is a bit difficult to find</li> <li>Honestly pleasantly pleased with this library since it has good lighting, good seating + outlets, and isn’t too quiet or crowded. The only con would probably be its location</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="doe">Doe</h4> <p>🏆 <em>Best architecture</em></p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Possible if in a more hidden location</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Personally hard to find if not at the large tables but even then, the outlets are connected to the lamp so larger powerblocks aren’t able to be plugged in</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Generally easy to find a seat with so many tables</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>One of the central libraries so lots of traffic and lots of general visitors because of the architecture</li> <li>Busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Echoey but quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Opens early and closes around 9 PM throughout weekdays and weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Beautiful architecture</li> <li>Connected with Bancroft, Moffitt, and Main Stacks</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/doe-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/doe-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/doe-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/doe.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> "Harry Potter"-esque interior </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="earth-sciences--map">Earth Sciences &amp; Map</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Not recommended</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>I think there were some next to the desks</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1/5</code> <ul> <li>Only saw like 1-3 tables</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Nobody goes here</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5/5</code> <ul> <li>Almost no noise</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes at 5 PM and not open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Located in one of the buildings near North Gate and is kind of hard to find</li> <li>Very old library containing lots of maps</li> <li>Closes early, wouldn’t recommend coming here to work for a long time</li> <li>I think only the people who work at the library go there</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="east-asian">East Asian</h4> <p>🏆 <em>Best views</em></p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Only possible if in a cubicle</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Difficult to find unless at table</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Personally thought it is difficult to find since the library isn’t too large</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Lots of traffic after noon</li> <li>Very busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Very quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes at 5 PM and not open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Probably the most beautiful library on campus with great views and natural sunlight</li> <li>Bookable rooms are available but can be difficult to find</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/east-asian-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/east-asian-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/east-asian-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/east-asian.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Views from top floor </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="engineering-kresge">Engineering (Kresge)</h4> <p>🏆 <em>Best for guaranteed seating to do short-term work</em></p> <p>NOTE: Review based on before renovation</p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Easy to do so</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Extremely easy to find throughout the library but kind of hard of cubicles ironically</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Lots of seating throughout the library, especially couch areas</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Very crowded since all of the engineering kids come here</li> <li>Very busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Talking is allowed so wouldn’t recommend coming here if you need to focus</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes late (I think midnight?) and open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Lots of bookable rooms - typically by CSM mentors</li> <li>Kind of musty</li> <li>Cool architecture, bunker style with an upper and lower floor</li> <li>Some unharmful homeless people</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/kresge-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/kresge-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/kresge-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/kresge.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Double-decker levels of Kresge </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="environmental-design-wurster">Environmental Design (Wurster)</h4> <p>🏆 Best for vibes</p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Wouldn’t recommend unless at the seating near the very edges of the library</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Generally available at the ends of the large tables</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Lots of tables so should be relatively easy to find</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Moderately filled throughout the day</li> <li>Surprisingly very busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>For a large library, very quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes late at 10 PM and open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>I love this library for some reason, I think it’s very spacious, clean, and quiet</li> <li>Only two bookable rooms - one is very large while the other is small</li> <li>Sometimes unharmful homeless people but not too often</li> <li>Two levels but I’ve never been/don’t know how to get to the second level (seems like a studio?)</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="ethnic-studies">Ethnic Studies</h4> <ul> <li>TBA</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="institute-of-governmental-studies">Institute of Governmental Studies</h4> <ul> <li>TBA</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="main-gardner-stacks">Main (Gardner) Stacks</h4> <p>🏆 Best for grinding</p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Easy to do so if in a cubicle and really quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Almost guaranteed to have an outlet anywhere you decide to sit (excluding couches)</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Lots of seating whether it be at the large tables, cubicles, “peer pressure” desks, or couches</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Moderately filled throughout the day but traffic comes in and out</li> <li>Extremely packed during exam season, do not recommend</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5/5</code> <ul> <li>Dead silent</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes late (I think midnight or 2 AM) and open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Very hard to navigate when coming for the first time</li> <li>Underground library with five floors</li> <li>Meeting rooms are generally easy to book and not too popular but most come with chalk boards</li> <li>Wi-Fi can be spotty at different levels of the library and generally no data down there</li> <li>Recommend coming here for long study sessions, feels great to leave afterwards to feel the fresh air</li> <li>Can be cold or stuffy temperature-wise</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/mainstacks-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/mainstacks-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/mainstacks-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/mainstacks.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> "Peer pressure" desks in Main Stacks </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="mathematics-statistics">Mathematics Statistics</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Easy to do so if at the upper floor cubicles</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Cubicles on top floor don’t have outlets except for a few</li> <li>Public computer area has seating and outlets on the ground</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Cubicles, tables, couches, desks</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Traffic comes in and out throughout the day but generally should be able to find a seat</li> <li>One of the “lesser known” libraries on campus since it’s located on the first floor of Evans Hall</li> <li>More busy during exam season but still less compared to other libraries</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Surprisingly quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes at 8 PM and not open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Can be difficult to find initially</li> <li>Very old, musty and small library</li> <li>Good place to pop in and do some work for a short amount of time</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="moffitt">Moffitt</h4> <p>🏆 <em>Best for eating</em></p> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">True</code></li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Usually available at the desks and cubicles (if you’re able to get a seat…)</li> <li>Love the outlets at 4th floor couch areas</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Extremely difficult to find seating with desks at popular floors (4 and 5) but easier to find seating at Floors 1, 3 and 5</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1/5</code> <ul> <li>Most popular library on campus since it’s in the middle and eating is allowed</li> <li>Very busy during exam season, DO NOT recommend</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">5/5</code> <ul> <li>Used to be 24 hour library but now closes at midnight and is open on weekends</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1/5</code> <ul> <li>Depends on floor <ul> <li>1: Chatter (not too loud)</li> <li>3: Chatter (not too loud)</li> <li>4: Loud</li> <li>5: Generally quiet but occasional murmuring</li> </ul> </li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Lots of bookable rooms on Floors 4 and 5 with whiteboards</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/moffitt-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/moffitt-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/libraries/moffitt-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/libraries/moffitt.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Views of the Glade from the fifth floor </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="morrison">Morrison</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code></li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Available at desks? But limited</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>2 floors but a few desks, mostly a lot of couches for reading</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Not as popular library because you’re only supposed to read there</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">1/5</code></li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>In an obscure location, closes relatively early and the second floor seems harder to access</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Do not use technology inside this library, you will get side-eyed</li> <li>Historical appearance</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="music">Music</h4> <ul> <li><strong>Eat:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">False</code> <ul> <li>Doable depending on location (yes for cubicles)</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Outlets:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">2/5</code> <ul> <li>Available at desks and cubicles</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Seating:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>3 floors but varying amounts of seating per floor (less on the top and basement floors)</li> <li>I love the cubicle area on the middle floor, lots of desks with outlets and is very private + quiet</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Crowdedness:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3.5/5</code> <ul> <li>Not as popular library</li> <li>More busy during exam season</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Noise:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">4/5</code> <ul> <li>Quiet throughout</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Accessibility:</strong> <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">3/5</code> <ul> <li>Closes semi-early (8 PM) and open on weekends until 5 PM</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>Comments</strong> <ul> <li>Don’t need Cal-ID to enter</li> <li>Beautiful library on the outside, kind of looks like Soda Hall (especially top floor)</li> <li>Ground to ceiling windows near some desks with views of Hearst Annex Field and walkways which can be distracting</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="social-research">Social Research</h4> <ul> <li>TBA</li> </ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="advice"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[reviews and rankings of uc berkeley's numerous libraries from a frequent lib-goer]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">thoughts on bronny james</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/thoughts-on-bronny-james/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="thoughts on bronny james"/><published>2024-07-06T10:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-07-06T10:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/thoughts-on-bronny-james</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/thoughts-on-bronny-james/"><![CDATA[<p>bruh why am i writing about lebron james’ son, not even about the Warriors or Stephen Curry 😭</p> <hr/> <p>I’m conflicted on Bronny James. As a Warriors fan, I’m obligated to dislike his father, Lebron James. I definitely am not a fan of him but I respect his impact on the game of basketball and his dedication to positively impact whatever team he’s on. The main reason why I dislike Lebron is because of his cockiness and ego — like yes, he’s a good basketball player but I think it’s very egotistical of him to deem himself “The King” when there are loads of great basketball players throughout history.</p> <p>To be fair, I haven’t watched Bronny play too much except for the occasional highlight post/reel that pops up on my Instagram feed. However, I’ve never been impressed by any of his highlights (I think one of his highlights during his first NBA summer league game was an easy steal and pass 💀).</p> <p>He was selected 55th overall in the second round of the NBA 2024 draft. Did he deserve to be drafted? No, and here are my reasons and thoughts circulating him.</p> <blockquote> <p><strong>What are the odds that he gets drafted AND to the Lakers, the same team his father is on?</strong></p> </blockquote> <p>Bronny is barely 6’2”. That’s considered extremely short in the NBA. In Stephen Curry’s scouting report, coaches said that he’d be unlikely to find success in the league because of his height, mind you Curry is 6’3”. The fact that the Lakers ended up drafting him is extremely suspicious to me… the nepotism at hand is <strong>CRAZY</strong>.</p> <blockquote> <p><strong>Bronny was not the star player at USC.</strong></p> </blockquote> <p>During the 25 games he played during his freshman season (typically 35-40 games per season), he only averaged 4.8 points per game. He also only started in six of those games. Usually, a player can make up for less PPG by contributing to other stats like rebounds or assists but he only averaged 2.8 rebounds and 2.1 assists. <em>Numbers don’t lie…</em></p> <blockquote> <p><strong>He had a cardiac arrest, he deserves some slack.</strong></p> </blockquote> <p>Yes, it’s unfortunate that incident happened to him. However, it’s a bit suspicious to me because Bronny is young, incredibly fit, and healthy with access to the best trainers and doctors available. The timing of his cardiac arrest was also strange since it was right before the start of the college season and there were no instances of heart failure in the past. I’m aware that heart problems do randomly occur for some people but these are just some factors I’m wary about. <em>Was this a planned accident to get the media less focused on his success in the upcoming season and draft? Who knows…</em></p> <blockquote> <p><strong>How did he go from being hesitant on staying at USC/playing in college basketball to enrolling in the NBA draft?</strong></p> </blockquote> <p>For any other NBA prospect, there is absolutely <strong>NO WAY</strong> they would get drafted with Bronny’s stats and caliber. He was considering transferring colleges but then somehow made it to the draft? Additionally, rookies are rarely paid millions when drafted but he signed a $7.9 million contract across 4 years. <strong>HE HAS NEVER EVEN PLAYED FOR THEM</strong>, he has proved none of his skills to the team yet. He definitely improved leading up to the draft combine but still not up to par to other players. Yes, his jersey and position on the team will bring in lots of revenue which the NBA ultimately is, a business, but please…</p> <p>All in all, I think it’s incredibly unfair that Bronny was drafted when there were so many other players who have equally worked as hard (arguably more to be honest) to get to that position as he did. At the same time, I feel bad for Bronny because he has an immense amount of pressure on him, being the firstborn son of “The King”. I kind of feel bad for him because he’s getting more scrutinized than others but at the same time, he was cocky enough to only accept workouts from 3 teams… I wish him the best in his career, with such a low bar he’s setting, he’s sure to beat the odds.</p> <p>Ironically enough, he already got injured after one game. I feel like most of this is Lebron’s doing since he’s a stats-chaser and wants them to be the first active father-son duo in the NBA but I don’t know — <em>doesn’t it feel unsettling knowing that what you achieved wasn’t rightfully deserved?</em> But then again, money can buy happiness, or in this case, a career lol.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[my perspective on lebron james jr]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">reflecting</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/reflecting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="reflecting"/><published>2024-06-15T12:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-06-15T12:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/reflecting</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/reflecting/"><![CDATA[<p><b></b></p> <p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">redacted</code> but sometimes it’s nice to just stop, rest, and think about life.</p> <hr/>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="opinions"/><category term="reflections"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[basketball is really cool]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">things i wish i knew before visiting japan</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/things-i-wish-i-knew-before-visiting-japan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="things i wish i knew before visiting japan"/><published>2024-05-26T15:59:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-26T15:59:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/things-i-wish-i-knew-before-visiting-japan</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/things-i-wish-i-knew-before-visiting-japan/"><![CDATA[<p><strong>[May 14, 2024]</strong> I’m currently in Japan while I’m drafting this post, unable to sleep because I randomly woke up at 2:30 AM and decided to work on this. This was my first time visiting Japan and the first international trip I’ve taken as a <em>competent</em> human being (aka not a kid). These are the things I wish I knew to make the travel process more seamless and the trip more fun — please don’t suffer like I did.</p> <p><strong>[May 26, 2024]</strong> I was bored and don’t have friends in Seattle so here I am, writing random nonsense to the void.</p> <hr/> <h3 id="my-itinerary">My Itinerary</h3> <p>My dad randomly called me one day in the middle of April saying that he needed to verify some information for filing my taxes, then ended up convincing me to take a week long trip to Japan immediately after my last final until the start of my internship. I truly have never been as stressed as I was during that time period but here are the trip specifications and distance covered:</p> <ul> <li><strong>Length:</strong> 5/11/2024 - 5/18/2024 <ul> <li>Stayed in Tokyo (1 night), Osaka (4 nights), Shinjuku City (1 night)</li> </ul> </li> <li><strong>5/11:</strong> Flight</li> <li><strong>5/12:</strong> Narita Airport –&gt; Tokyo</li> <li><strong>5/13:</strong> Osaka</li> <li><strong>5/14:</strong> Kyoto</li> <li><strong>5/15:</strong> Kyoto</li> <li><strong>5/16:</strong> Nara</li> <li><strong>5/17:</strong> Shinjuku City</li> <li><strong>5/18:</strong> Shinjuku City –&gt; Narita Airport, flight</li> </ul> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="prior-to-trip">Prior to Trip</h3> <ul> <li>Make sure your cards are usable abroad.</li> <li>Add the transit cards (Suica, PASMOS, ICOCA) to your Apple Wallet (if you have an Apple device). <ul> <li>Click the <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">+</code> sign to add a card</li> <li>Click <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Transit Card</code></li> <li>Under the “Japan” section, click your preferred option (I used Suica)</li> <li>Adding money is through the cards on your Apple Wallet <ul> <li>Make sure you have a Mastercard on there</li> </ul> </li> </ul> </li> <li>Plan your trip in advance, especially places that are a “must-visit”. <ul> <li>Make reservations for popular restaurants</li> </ul> </li> <li>ZipAir <ul> <li>Read the fine details regarding baggage weights</li> <li>Bring your own food on the flight (it doesn’t add to your carry-on weight)</li> <li>Have activities ready for the flight (ex: download movies) because there isn’t an entertainment system provided</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p>Since you’re in a foreign country, make sure that you’ll be able to use your cards. Call the bank beforehand and ask them to not block your cards because otherwise, the detectors think there’s a fraud and then you won’t be able to use your cards.</p> <p>On your Apple Wallet, make sure that you have a Mastercard on there. Those cards are guaranteed to work to add money to your transportation cards whereas only some Visa cards have proven to work.</p> <blockquote> <p>The transit systems cards in Japan (Suica/PASMOS/ICOCA) are used to pay for the subway stations and buses. Generally, it’s a physical card but there’s an IC chip shortage so they aren’t giving them out to visitors as much (a “Welcome Suica Card” exists but isn’t easily available anymore). The card can also be used for purchases too at some stores (in my experience, mainly convenience stores). Get this card instead of buying paper tickets for every ride.</p> </blockquote> <p><strong>HIGHLY, HIGHLY RECOMMEND</strong> planning the majority of your trip in advance, especially factoring in transportation.</p> <ul> <li>What cities do you want to visit? <ul> <li>Book hotels at strategic locations (ex: live in Osaka if you want to visit Kyoto and Nara)</li> </ul> </li> <li>What activities do you want to do/visit? What places do you want to eat at?</li> </ul> <p>I didn’t plan any of our itinerary until the night before each day so it was really tiring. Additionally, the lack of planning left us unable to see all the places we wanted to visit or try popular restaurants (most require a reservation). Navigating through the public transit system was also a struggle because it’s hard to initially get a grasp of due to the magnitude and language barrier.</p> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="getting-from-narita-airport-to-tokyo-and-back">Getting from Narita Airport to Tokyo (and back)</h3> <p>All I knew before arriving in Japan was that it’d take a little over an hour to get from the Narita Airport to our hotel in Tokyo. However, I was clueless and didn’t think to even consider how to pay for that transportation, let alone what specific type of transportation it would be.</p> <p><u>What I Did:</u></p> <p>After getting our Suica cards set up, we took the train to Tokyo (I think it was the Narita Express) but we just tapped through the scanners and didn’t buy physical paper tickets. We sat at a random section which ended up being the “Reserved Seats” section — this area is checked by the train workers who told us to move to another section (so embarrassing).</p> <p><u>What I Recommend You Do:</u></p> <ul> <li>Search for the most convenient option available (Narita Express tended to be on the more expensive side) <ul> <li>If you have the time and more familarity with the transit system, take the regular subway</li> <li>Narita Express is the most direct option</li> </ul> </li> <li>Narita Express: Each train is split into reserved seating (more expensive) vs. non-reserved seating <ul> <li>Non-reserved seating is at the back of the train, usually cars 1-5</li> <li>It’ll say on the train car and signs which car is reserved seating or not</li> </ul> </li> </ul> <p>When traveling back to the airport, I decided to take the regular subway system will ended up taking FOREVER for some strange reason (literally took us a little over 3 hours to get from Tokyo to Narita Airport). It was quite traumatic and stressful because we almost missed our flight.</p> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="getting-from-tokyo-to-osaka-and-back">Getting from Tokyo to Osaka (and back)</h3> <p>Traveling from Tokyo to the Osaka area is fairly common and the easiest way is by taking a bullet train (Shinkansen). The ride is a little over 3 hours which is extremely fast considering the amount of miles covered. The train is comfortable and there are bathrooms onboard, as well as (adequate) Wi-Fi.</p> <p>To ride on this train:</p> <ul> <li>Wait in the really long line to get physical tickets with an attendant <ul> <li>Mobile Suica cards don’t work at the machines because those only accept physical cards</li> </ul> </li> <li>Payment can be through your physical cards like Visa (not Suica)</li> <li>You’ll receive a physical ticket that you’ll insert through the gate (which will be ejected out) in addition to tapping your Suica card against the scanner</li> </ul> <blockquote> <p>DO NOT lose your physical ticket. If you do, you’ll need to pay the cost of that ticket again (~$94).</p> </blockquote> <p>I lost my physical ticket near my seat and talked to an attendant at the counter. The company’s policy is that everyone has to pay the original cost on top of what was previously paid if the workers at both train stations are unable to find your physical ticket.</p> <p>Travelers have the option to pay for “reserved” (more expensive but guaranteed seats) or “non-reserved” seating. Make sure to pay attention to which train cars are for “non-reserved” seating — typically cars 1-5 at the back.</p> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="cities-visited">Cities Visited</h3> <p>Here are my reviews and reflections for the cities I visited, attractions I saw, and restaurants/food I ate. Feel free to contact me to see the (messy) spreadsheet itinerary I made (for visual learners), or check out my Beli for more detailed food reviews. Click on each picture to see a zoomed in version as well!</p> <p><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">*</code> = transit day</p> <h4 id="tokyo-">Tokyo *</h4> <p><strong>Duration:</strong> 3 hours</p> <ul> <li>Dinner @ Ichiran Asakusa</li> <li>Discovery of Japan’s 7-11 stores</li> <li>Tokyo Skytree view from hotel</li> </ul> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/ichiran.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/ichiran.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/ichiran.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/ichiran.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Ichiran Asakusa is a popular ramen restaurant that features solo dining via sitting in a private setting at the bar counter. The quantity was great, especially for the price and there were lots of people lined up for this restaurant. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Rating: 8/10</code></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/tokyoskytree.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/tokyoskytree.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/tokyoskytree.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/tokyoskytree.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>After dinner, we walked across Sumida River and saw views of the Tokyo Skytree. We entered our first 7-11 and bought ice cream cones, as well as various breakfast items there.</p> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="osaka-">Osaka *</h4> <p><strong>Duration:</strong> Late afternoon + evening</p> <ul> <li>Breakfast: 7/11 pastries + milk</li> <li>Lunch @ one of Shin-Osaka Station’s terrible restaurants</li> <li>Cheesecake from Rikuro’s Namba Main Branch</li> <li>Dontonbori</li> <li>Tsutenkaku Tower</li> <li>Dinner @ Kura Sushi Shinsekai Tsutenkaku (terrible)</li> </ul> <p>Since this was a travel day where we went from Tokyo to Osaka, we only had a few hours to spend exploring Osaka. When going to the station, it had started raining as we were lugging our suitcases across the streets. A big culture shock was seeing how EVERYONE uses umbrellas, even for the slightest bit of rain. We got a bunch of side-eyes since we didn’t bring umbrellas and didn’t want to purchase one.</p> <p>The bullet train was a bit of a struggle and after arriving at Shin-Osaka Station, we were famished and chose a random restaurant to eat at. I forgot the name of it but we all ordered this collagen chicken noodle soup. I’m pretty sure my parents got rizzed up by the word “collagen”. The noodle soup was actually delicious but the bowl was TINY and it was so expensive. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Rating: 6/10</code></p> <p>The jiggly Japanese cheesecake has grown significantly in popularity so it was a must-try for me, especially since my mom loves cheesecake. We had purchased a small cheesecake pastry from 7-11 the day prior and consumed it on the bullet train — it was DELICIOUS. Rikuro’s Namba Main Branch had a huge line outside of it but the wait was very short. The cheesecake was pretty cheap ($8-9) and tasted good, though the 7-11 one might be tastier… My picture is quite disappointing though because the heat and condensation from the box made the top of the cheesecake flaccid, but luckily it was still a little bit jiggly! <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Rating: 8.5/10</code></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/shinosakafood.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/shinosakafood.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/shinosakafood.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/shinosakafood.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/cheesecake.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/cheesecake.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/cheesecake.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/cheesecake.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>We had some difficulty finding our hotel because I was directionally challenged and navigated us to the wrong hotel with a very similar name. After relaxing for a bit, we strolled through Dontonbori, an area famous for its various shops and foods. We were able to see the Tsutenkaku Tower while walking through.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/tsutower.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/tsutower.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/tsutower.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/tsutower.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>For some odd reason, search results told me that Kura Sushi was a good place to eat at. This information is incorrect — it’s just a revolving sushi chain that when compared to U.S. prices is really good, but overall not the best quality and value in Japan. Unfortunately, this ended up being the only sushi we ate in Japan because my parents aren’t the biggest fans of raw fish (PLS, why are we in Japan then?!). My mom struggled throughout this meal but my dad was a trooper and did pretty well. The game was quite lame though, we turned in ~23 plates but only received one prize. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Rating: 6/10</code></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/kurasushi.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/kurasushi.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/kurasushi.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/kurasushi.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="kyoto">Kyoto</h4> <p><strong>Duration:</strong> 2 days</p> <p><u>Day 1</u></p> <ul> <li>Brunch @ A Happy Pancake Kyoto</li> <li>Nishiki Market</li> <li>Kodaiji Temple, Maruyama Park, Yuzenen Garden</li> <li>Dinner @ Gyukatshu Kyoto Katsugyu - Kyoto Station</li> <li>Uniqlo shopping</li> </ul> <p>Growing up, my family rarely ate out and operated under a very minimalistic lifestyle. We literally would bring basically our entire kitchen when going on roadtrips so eating out is somewhat foreign to us. However, food is so cheap in Japan that it wasn’t that big of an impact to eat out for every meal.</p> <p>I found “A Happy Pancake” from one of my friends and we ate there for brunch. I’ve attempted making Japanese soufflé pancakes at home which were somewhat of a success, but these were the professional ones that I needed to try. The wait was a little long because of the line and the time the chefs took to make each dish with care. I ordered some matcha brown sugar pancake dish which was really good and just the right quantity because I hit my sugar quota at the end. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Rating: 8.5/10</code></p> <p>Nishiki Market is a popular tourist attraction that is essentially a fish market with lots of shops and street food. Since we had just eaten, we didn’t really buy that many snacks but we did try these mochi strawberries since the strawberries rizzed me up. A little on the expensive side but the strawberries were SO GOOD.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/happypancake.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/happypancake.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/happypancake.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/happypancake.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/mochistrawb.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/mochistrawb.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/mochistrawb.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/mochistrawb.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>After the market, we visited Kodaiji Temple, Maruyama Park, and Yuzenen Garden. Honestly, I’m not the biggest temple fan because they ultimately are all essentially the same… but the history behind temples and shrines are quite interesting. Maruyama Park was quite big and we spent a lot of time there because my mom was tired and I needed to find a restaurant to go to for dinner.</p> <p>Gyukatsu Kyoto Katsugyu kept popping up and since my parents have never really tried chicken katsu before, we decided to go there. Turns out, this wasn’t a chicken katsu place but was instead a wagyu katsu restaurant. My parents hate raw meat so they were really worried but there ended up being a tiny stove where you can cook your meat prior to eating it. My parents LOVED this restaurant and the wait was pretty short considering the line. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Rating: 9/10</code></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/firsttemples-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/firsttemples-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/firsttemples-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/firsttemples.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/gyukatsu.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/gyukatsu.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/gyukatsu.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/gyukatsu.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>We were on the way to the subway station when my mom spotted a Uniqlo. We ended up spending probably two hours there shopping, such low prices.</p> <p><u>Day 2</u></p> <ul> <li>Lunch @ Kijurou</li> <li>Arashiyama area (Tenryu-ji temple, Shishiku garden, Arashiyama Park, Arashiyama bamboo forest, Togetsukyo Bridge)</li> <li>Strolling through Arashiyama and eating small desserts</li> <li>Dinner @ Genki</li> </ul> <p>We had already tried wagyu at the restaurant before but that wasn’t the real deal. We had zero reservations at restaurants but luckily, Kijurou doesn’t accept reservations and is located near the Arashiyama area we were planning on visiting. Side note: my dad kept pronouncing “wagyu” as “wag-niu” — “nit” in Cantonese stands for pee.</p> <p>We ordered the sirloin set with 150 grams of meat. My mom threw such a fit because she refused to eat the meat after finding out that there wasn’t a little stove like the restaurant we went to yesterday. She ended up asking a server to cook the meat well-done… it was quite embarrassing. Overall, the food was pretty solid but the tofu thing was a little strange… I don’t think I ate it correctly. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Rating: 8/10</code></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/kijurou.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/kijurou.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/kijurou.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/kijurou.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>We visited the Arashiyama area afterwards which consisted of the Tenry-ji temple, Shishiku garden, Arashiyama Park, Arashiyama bamboo forest, and Togetsukyo Bridge. We paid $8 to enter the temple and garden which was worth it because the garden was pretty. The bamboo forest was packed as usual and a little underwhelming to be honest. However, we went to one of the viewpoints which overlooked the river and was quite nice.</p> <p>It was INSANE how many tourists there are in the Arashiyama area though. Literally where did all of these people come from…</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/garden.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/garden.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/garden.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/garden.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/bamboo-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/bamboo-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/bamboo-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/bamboo.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/river.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/river.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/river.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/river.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>While strolling through, we got some desserts and I saw a Cremia ice cream stand. I saw someone talking about that brand on Instagram and decided to try it even though it was on the more expensive side. To be honest, the ice cream didn’t taste that special and the cone was structurally unstable because the wafer kept leaking. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Rating: 6.5/10</code></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/cremia.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/cremia.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/cremia.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/cremia.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Since we’re in a new country, one of my priorities was trying the different foods available there. Okonomiyaki is essentially a Japanese pizza which Osaka is known for. I found a restaurant called Genki that had a lot of reviews specializing in this dish and turned out to be a local joint. The restaurant itself is small and probably a bar because every customer is forced to order drinks. My dad ordered my mom a beer and that was also the first time I’ve ever drank with my parents.</p> <p>I got the pork modern okonomiyaki which included yakisoba noodles on the bottom. The sauce itself was a new flavor I haven’t tried before but it was pretty good, just a little heavy.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/beers.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/beers.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/beers.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/beers.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/genki.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/genki.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/genki.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/genki.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="nara">Nara</h4> <p><strong>Duration:</strong> 1 day</p> <ul> <li>Breakfast @ Horiuchi-kajitsuen</li> <li>Nakatanidou - mochi men oogabooga-ing</li> <li>Nara Park ft deer</li> <li>Lunch @ Kamaiki Udon</li> <li>Isu-en Garden, Todaiji Nigatsu-do</li> <li>Supermarket</li> <li>Dinner @ McDonalds</li> </ul> <p>I attempted making Japanese fruit sandwiches with my friends before but it was a disaster. If you know me, I also can’t survive without fruit because I need to eat it every day. Unfortunately, fruit is difficult to find in Japan and is pricey. I learned from Reddit that to find these sandwiches, you have to search “fruit parlor”.</p> <p>The shop above was in Nara and honestly really good. The bread was so fluffy and all of the fruits were sweet. One of the sandwiches was a little odd because it was kind of like a salad + imitation crab + apples on some bread. However, this ended up being a balanced combo since our other two sandwiches were sweet.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/strawbsando.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/strawbsando.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/strawbsando.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/strawbsando.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/fruitsando.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/fruitsando.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/fruitsando.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/fruitsando.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/saladsando.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/saladsando.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/saladsando.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/saladsando.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Since we missed the monkey park at Arashiyama, I wanted to see the deer in Nara Park. They are quite literally everywhere in the park and my parents loved them. One deer even bit my mom’s cardigan which she wasn’t the biggest fan of. Throughout the 1.5 hours spent there, my mission was getting a selfie with a deer. It was mostly unsuccessful since I have no rizz.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/deer.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/deer.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/deer.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/deer.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>The mochi slapping men have risen to fame which is why we had to see them in action as well. We arrived at the shop around 10:30 AM and it was already pretty packed, though they have different performances. I’m not the biggest mochi fan so it wasn’t revolutionary to me but I’m sure it was quality mochi.</p> <p>We hadn’t eaten udon yet in Japan so I found a restaurant that apparently received a Michelin star years prior. Unfortunately, I thought that the meal was pretty standard. Honestly, Marugame Udon might be better…</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/mochi.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/mochi.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/mochi.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/mochi.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/kamaiki.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/kamaiki.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/kamaiki.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/kamaiki.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>We visited the rest of the area in Nara and I was pretty interested in the history there because I started to actually read most of the signs HAHA. We ended up eating at McDonalds because I wanted to try the Japanese items on the menus.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/temple.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/temple.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/temple.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/temple.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Throughout this trip, I was admittedly mean to my mom and ended up making her cry during dinner. She’s a lot older and slower than me but incompetency/slowness is my biggest pet peeve which got on my nerves. I feel really bad about it and should apologize to her…</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/mcd.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/mcd.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/mcd.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/mcd.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/fries.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/fries.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/fries.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/fries.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p><br/></p> <h4 id="shinjuku-city-">Shinjuku City *</h4> <p><strong>Duration:</strong> Late afternoon + evening, 1 hr the next day</p> <ul> <li>Breakfast &amp; Lunch: Various 7/11 pastries + milk</li> <li>Bullet train from Osaka to Shinjuku City</li> <li>Hair cut + dye @ youres hair 新宿WEST店</li> <li>Dinner @ Fūunji</li> <li>Daiso + some mall in Shinjuku City</li> </ul> <p>Since this was another travel day, we spent very little time exploring Shinjuku City. The main priority on the agenda was getting hair cuts since that was what my mom wanted to do the most. I had previously searched online for hair salons and almost all had a reservation/appointment system.</p> <p>Turns out, hair salons prefer customers to schedule appointments (even if it’s an hour before). We had walked into a salon and they were fully booked, so I found another salon called “youres hair 新宿WEST店”. I hastily made appointments for my mother and I literally an hour before our actual slots.</p> <p>This was the first time I had professional hair treatment in a salon, in addition to dyeing my hair (rip to my hair virginity). Typically, my mom made my aunt or random acquaintances cut my hair on an old and smelly porch in my uncle’s backyard. I had quite the opposite experience since the salon itself was very clean and sophisticated. My hair was EXTREMELY long since I hadn’t had a haircut for over a year.</p> <p>Due to the language barrier, I communicated with my hair stylist via Google Translate which honestly wasn’t too bad. Since I was so inexperienced in the hair world, I literally didn’t understand some of the phrases he was using and told him to just “do whatever you think is best”.</p> <p>We had shown up so late in the afternoon (~5 PM) so he informed me that I wouldn’t be able to get highlights or bleach my hair. I ended up coloring my hair to a darker brown in addition to a hair cut.</p> <p>First, I got my hair slightly wet for the coloring process. Afterwards, he applied the dye onto my hair and I ended up looking like a seran wrap conehead. I had to wait a bit for the dye to color my hair and the salon provided tablets with Amazon Prime and drinks (tea) for their customers to consume. I played some fruit game on my Huawei tablet :D.</p> <p>Once the dye settled onto my hair, my stylist washed my hair and massaged my hair which was a nice experience — I almost fell asleep. My initial reaction after seeing my colored hair was that I looked weird. He trimmed my hair but I had to tell him a few times that I wanted to chop off a bunch of inches because I was paying so much money for this. He gave me surface layers and curled my hair at the end.</p> <p>I thought I looked REALLY WEIRD but my parents told me it looked good. In the meantime, my mom got a hair cut and perm which looked great on her. My dad was just happy because there was Wi-Fi while he was waiting for 2+ hours.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/reaction-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/reaction-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/reaction-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/reaction.jpeg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="caption"> My sister's reaction to my hair </div> </div> <p>Since the hair appointments took so long, we only had time for dinner. Fūunji is a popular dipping udon restaurant which had an ENORMOUS line. The seating is only at the counter and as you’re eating, the line of people waiting is directly behind you, staring at your soul while eating. That part was a little uncomfortable but the udon was really good. <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Rating: 8.5/10</code></p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/fuunji.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/fuunji.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/fuunji.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/fuunji.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>Afterwards, my parents and I went to several 7-11 stores to buy food for our upcoming flight and search for the coveted 2% low-fat 7/11 milk carton. That was literally the only thing my dad kept raving about — how delicious that milk was. We went to four different 7-11’s and unfortunately exited empty-handed. Perhaps, that milk carton is only available in Tokyo(?) or maybe it is so scrumptious that it sells out quickly…</p> <p>We had planned on spending our last day shopping but the hair appointment took so long that most stores were closed by then. As such, I planned on allocating 1.5 hours to shop before taking the subway to the airport. What a terrible idea…</p> <p>We briefly shopped at a Daiso but I literally could not locate the LOFT store in a mall. That wasted about 20 minutes and by then, it was nearing too close to the time we should depart for the airport. I decided to just navigate us to the airport but the station in Shinjuku City was especially confusing and for some reason, all of the subways we traveled on had random transfers/stops. The ride to the airport took almost four hours when it should have taken a little over one hour…</p> <p>In addition, ZipAir requires passengers to arrive one hour before departure at the latest and we were really close to that deadline. As we were rushing, my mom fell too ;-;</p> <p>All in all, that train ride was extremely stressful because if I had missed my flight, I wouldn’t be able to go to Seattle the next day since ZipAir flights only operate once a day.</p> <p>Once we arrived at our gate, we wanted to use up the remaining coins we had at an ice cream vending machine. The ice cream bar depicted below was the most expensive one purchased whilst also being the smallest. I shared the bar with my parents since it was the last one but I had completely forgotten that my dad was sick. As a result, I got a sore throat on the flight and ended up falling extremely ill after the flight (in fact, I’m still sick more than a week later as I’m writing this).</p> <p>During takeoff, I noticed that the plane’s wing was a little suspicious and unstable. I’m no expert on aircraft but that doesn’t look very safe… perks of choosing cheap flights! Usually, I welcome death but I had never feared my death as much as I did on that flight because I didn’t want my parents to pass away.</p> <p>I had read on Reddit that the 7-11 egg salad sandwiches were delicious so obviously, I had to try one myself. I bought one for the flight back but unfortunately, it got squished.</p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/icecreambar.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/icecreambar.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/icecreambar.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/icecreambar.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/susplane-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/susplane-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/susplane-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/susplane.gif" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/blogs/japan/eggsalad.JPG-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/eggsalad.JPG-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/blogs/japan/eggsalad.JPG-1400.webp 1400w," sizes="95vw" type="image/webp"/> <img src="/assets/img/blogs/japan/eggsalad.JPG" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <p>During the flight to Japan, I watched “The Idea of You” which is a horrible choice when you’re sitting next to your parents. On the flight back, I watched “Barbie” which made me fall asleep two times. <em>slayyyy</em> 💅</p> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="takeaways">Takeaways</h3> <ol> <li>The public transportation system there is SO GOOD but also simultaneously so overwhelming.</li> <li>Everything in Japan is so cheap compared to the USA. Travel LIGHT, you’ll want to buy stuff (in fact, do because the yen has depreciated so much).</li> <li>Food is infinitely better in Japan. 7/11 is FANTASTIC.</li> <li>Society is kind of “old” but technology (especially transportation) is strangely advanced?</li> <li>Why are there SO MANY PEOPLE at the subway stations and everywhere in general? Where did they spawn from…</li> <li>People use umbrellas for the smallest amounts of rain. I’m from California where people freak out over rain and even I think the umbrella usage is ridiculous — it was literally for DRIZZLE.</li> <li>Enter the bus through the middle without paying but when leaving, exit through the front entrance after paying via tapping your Suica card.</li> <li>Japan is not very accessibility-friendly. Lugging suitcases across flights of stairs is terrible.</li> </ol> <p><br/></p> <h3 id="tldr">TLDR</h3> <p>Traveling with parents is difficult and don’t go on a vacation that you haven’t planned for right after finals and before another trip. Also, don’t share food with sick people (but the food is FIRE there).</p> <p>Japan has a bit of a … stain in my perspective so I’ll be needing some time away from this country. It’s not them, it’s me.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="travel"/><category term="advice"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[essentials you should know as a first time visitor to japan]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">why blog?</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/why-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="why blog?"/><published>2024-05-12T12:24:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-12T12:24:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/why-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2024/why-blog/"><![CDATA[<p><b></b></p> <p>👋 Hello stranger reading this! I’m not sure why you’re here but this post explains why I want to blog.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="so-why">so why?</h2> <p><b></b></p> <p>A lot of people have told me that I’m a really quiet person and that they want to get to know me better. I’ve also been informed that people want to know what’s going on in my head. Truth be told, I’m usually “no thoughts, head empty”. I tend to not overthink things and mainly live (mostly) in the present because life is so unpredictable, something might happen to flip my world upside down so why bother planning every detail?</p> <p>When attempting to make my personal website years ago, I looked at a bunch of other websites for <em>inspiration</em> and I liked the aspect of having a blog/forum of my own opinions and thoughts. I found that section of those sites extremely appealing to read through since it was a way to get to know those people better. Specifically, UC Berkeley’s <a href="https://cs161.org">CS 161</a> course has a <a href="https://pedagogy.cs161.org/">pedagogy blog</a> that I found <strong>especially</strong> fascinating and thought-provoking. Thus, I wanted a persistent means of sharing my advice or opinions online.</p> <p>Personally, I don’t think anyone will read any of my posts because I’m boring but for a long time, I wanted to share a couple of my opinions and have a “diary” of some sort to see how my thinking has changed and/or transitioned over time. I love data and recording miniscule details so this is another means for that.</p> <p>Medium is another blog forum site which I’ve used before but there are article reading restrictions on that platform, in addition to me not wanting people to get notified when I post which is why I’m choosing to post on my own site.</p> <p>These opinions will be only affiliated with me and (probably) not edited or proof-read thoroughly, it’s just a method of me to thought dump and reflect as my life progresses. In actuality, it’s probably just me wasting my time by procrastinating. Hopefully I’ll be able to post semi-frequently during any downtime I have but we’ll see… 🤡</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="random"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this post explains why I created a blog]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">KDr-awe-ma Opinions &amp;amp; Recommendations</title><link href="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2021/kdrama/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="KDr-awe-ma Opinions &amp;amp; Recommendations"/><published>2021-12-09T12:24:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-12-09T12:24:00+00:00</updated><id>https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2021/kdrama</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://christyquang.github.io/blog/2021/kdrama/"><![CDATA[<p><b></b></p> <p>I’m too lazy to copy over my original blog post to here so if you want to read it, please click the link below. I apologize in advance, that post is quite cringe and outdated as well.</p> <hr/> <h2 id="link">link</h2> <p><b></b></p> <p><a href="https://aweberkeley.medium.com/kdrama-opinions-recommendations-1a9ee7b9eb37">Original Medium post</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="posts"/><category term="opinions"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[this post was originally published on UC Berkeley's AWE Medium account and was my project under the Operations committee]]></summary></entry></feed>